Game. I'm ready, Director.
[BRIGHT MUSIC PLAYING]
[STAFF] Five! Four!
[VICE] Oh, wait a second.
Let's pray first.
Let's ask for a blessing first.
In the name of the Father,
of the Son,
and of the Holy Spirit,
Amen.
Lord God, thank you so much
for this day.
Thank you so much for letting us
stay in your world,
and for blessing us so much.
Thank you, Lord, for giving us
so many opportunities.
An opportunity to receive
your blessings.
An opportunity to give
and receive love.
An opportunity to use
the talent you've granted us.
An opportunity to work.
An opportunity to entertain
our viewers.
An opportunity to serve
to our colleagues.
An opportunity for us all
to meet and have fun.
An opportunity to make
content with our program
that aims to bring happiness to
many Filipinos around the world.
And thank you very much,
Lord Jesus Christ.
We know you'll guide us
all the way
from the beginning until
the end of our program.
Fill our studio
with laughter, positivity,
happiness, and liveliness.
We pray that we'll always
have a smile on our faces.
We pray that we start and
end the show filled with joy.
We also pray that our guests
and everyone here with us
will have a great time here
so they can have stories to tell
people when they return home.
We hope that we can create
some wonderful core memories
that we will carry with us
even when time passes by.
Thank you very much,
Lord Jesus Christ.
The success and glory
of our show is all yours.
Thank you very much.
We know that
this episode will be great.
In Jesus' name we pray,
Amen.
In the name of the Father,
of the Son,
and of the Holy Spirit,
Amen.
Let's go!
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
Ah, that's all right.
Okay.
Okay, so I will enter again
from the door,
and then pretend like
it's your first time seeing me.
- [AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
- Is that all right?
So just act like that.
Act like for the first time
in six years,
we've finally seen
each other again.
Is that okay?
- [AUDIENCE SHOUTING] Yes!
- Okay.
And when you see me,
act like you really love me.
Act as if you don't see
anything wrong
with everything I do on TV.
Act like you fully accept
all of me, you know.
So we're just going
to fool ourselves a little bit.
[VICE] Let's go.
Come on, my feet
are hurting already.
[STAFF] Hold it!
[VICE] First...
Wait a minute.
[VICE] Okay, I'm ready.
[STAFF] Five! Four!
Three! Two! One!
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
Yes!
Gandang Gabi,
Kapamilya and Kapuso!
[AUDIENCE] Gandang Gabi Vice!
[VICE] Oh my god!
I missed that greeting!
Gandang Gabi!
Good evening!
Good evening to all of you!
I missed you!
I...
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
I think you were also here
the last time we were here.
- So you're all still alive!
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
How fantastic!
[VICE] None of you were beaten
by the pandemic!
- You're all still here. Yes!
- [AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
But I think my Little Ponies
got a bit chubbier.
Oh my god, I'm so happy!
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
Here we go!
We've finally seen
each other again.
We're all together again
every Sunday night
on Gandang Gabi Vice!
[CHEERING]
[VICE] I'm so happy.
Are you so happy?
[AUDIENCE] Yes!
Are you excited?
My gosh! Did you miss GGV?
[AUDIENCE] Yes!
Wow! I feel so happy.
I missed this so much and
I also missed you all so much.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
I missed all the hijinks
we used to do here.
I missed the episodes when
we had more bleeps
than scenes aired.
I missed
our controversial episodes!
We're going to make
more of those now!
We're going back
to our messy antics!
[LAUGHTER SFX]
How fun. I missed you all.
Group hug.
Wow, look at the audience
in the middle.
They look like
they're the board of judges,
here to judge us today.
[CHUCKLES] They look like
representatives sent by MTRCB.
They look like they were sent by
the management, the advertisers,
and the suppliers from
our last season
who haven't been paid yet.
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
- They're all here.
[VICE] But let's come
and talk to them.
There. Let's go here.
Hi, sir! Gandang Gabi!
Gandang Gabi Vice!
- What's your name?
- Jason.
[VICE] Jason, can you
please stand up?
Please stand up for
just a second.
Ah, you're already standing.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
- Sir!
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
This is the new season of GGV
on GMA.
Have you really watched GGV
from our first seasons?
Yes, I also watched the uncut
versions on YouTube.
Oh, really?
You like things that are uncut?
Yes.
I'm personally not a big fan
of things that are uncut.
I prefer the edited versions.
Just kidding. Okay.
What's your favorite or
most memorable episode of GGV
that you've watched?
The reunion episode of
Palibhasa Lalake.
Ah! The one with Richard Gomez,
Joey Marquez, and John Estrada.
When they revealed
who was dating who.
Yes! How fun.
So you like it when our guests
are from the 90s and 80s, right?
- Yes, yes.
- Really?
So what are you looking forward
to watch this time?
Well, you have
a wider reach now.
You can have both Kapuso
and Kapamilya guests.
So you will be able
to invite more people now.
Not only is my reach wider now,
I'm looser now too.
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
- Right.
Of course, that's because
we can afford loose change now.
Don't be green-minded.
But I'm also excited to be with
people I haven't interviewed yet
from GMA.
Because I guess
99% of our guests
have come from ABS-CBN, right?
But we are freer now,
so we can talk to more people!
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
- Yes!
Which GMA artist would you like
to see me chat with?
- Dingdong Dantes.
- Ah, Dingdong Dantes.
But he's been a guest
on GGV twice already.
Where were you when
we aired those episodes?
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
- Sorry, sorry.
So you don't always
watch GGV then.
I don't want to talk
to you anymore.
You only watch sometimes.
Are you one of those people
who only watch us sometimes,
but still bash us?
- No, I'm not!
- Oh, you're not one of them.
But thank you very much.
What brought you here?
Does the production team
owe you money?
- No.
- Oh, none?
So you just want to experience
the first episode of
the new season of GGV?
- Yes.
- Thank you very much.
Yes!
And as you can see,
since we have a new season,
we have a new home!
We've exhausted
our previous home already.
It's gone through
a lot of trials.
Disaster, rain, typhoons,
floods, and earthquakes.
It's been haunted
with ghosts too.
So now, we have
a brand new home.
And since it's very new,
I've invited some people over.
I invited you all to come over
into my new home,
and to join me
in my house blessing.
But I'm sorry because
I was too busy preparing myself,
so I forgot to prepare
my house properly.
So as you can see,
this was just delivered here.
We had a hard time looking
for a sponsor who would
accept payment in installments
for 12 years.
You know what the industry
is going through right now,
so we can't pay in one go,
you know.
This was just delivered,
so I hadn't prepared it yet.
I did my makeup first and
focused on how I looked
because I can't greet guests
without looking pretty, right?
But...
I looked beautiful when
you all came over, right?
["ANGEL BABY" BY
TROYE SIVAN PLAYING]
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
- That's how you do it.
[VICE] I look like an idiot
on the logo again, don't I?
You've missed that too,
haven't you?
The way I look like
I'm falling over.
It seems like I look younger,
don't I?
[AUDIENCE] Yes!
Of course, celebrities like
to age backwards nowadays.
We like to look as if
we're getting younger.
But since my house is brand new,
I don't want to feel lonely,
of course.
I'm done with my era of
being lonely and alone.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
I'm more used to being
with people now.
So in my new home, I'll be
joined with new housemates.
They will also be with you
every Sunday aside from me.
Where are they?
I already told them that
we have a house blessing.
Why are they still not here?
I even arrived before them.
But they were
already here earlier.
They received the delivery.
Tetay! Verna!
[VICE SQUEALS]
- [TETAY WHOOPING]
- Gandang Gabi Vice!
Gandang Gabi Vice!
[VICE] Hey! Where have you been?
Our visitors are already here.
We'll call you again later
when we need you.
I'm also one of
your partners here, Meme!
My gosh, I already said that...
I already told you to receive
the furniture I had delivered.
I didn't ask you to buy
a propane tank.
I was doing the laundry earlier,
so I just picked this up too.
But wait a minute,
let's greet them first.
One, two, three.
[IN UNISON] Gandang Gabi Vice!
Yes!
They will be my new housemates
in our new home.
- Meet Tetay and Verna. Yes.
- Hello!
You've already seen Verna on
Breaking Muse on It's Showtime.
You've also seen Tetay
tag along with us sometimes.
He vlogs and he also appears
on It's Showtime sometimes,
as well as on other programs
on GMA and ABS-CBN.
- You really came prepared, huh?
- Of course!
- You came too ready.
- Well, look at yourself.
I prepared for this, Meme.
For the first time, I think
a mandarin might be bitter.
[VERNA CHUCKLES]
Usually, a mandarin
tastes sweet,
but this one looks bitter!
- This is not a mandarin, Meme.
- So what is it?
This is Sharmaine.
- Oh, you've changed.
- Yes.
So you've changed your name.
You should've changed faces too.
- My gosh!
- [VERNA AND TETAY CHUCKLE]
If a papaya soap is like this,
I don't want to use it anymore.
If she was a papaya soap,
would you use it?
- Well, I'm beautiful.
- Her figure's like a papaya.
But isn't her face like
that of a sapodilla?
[LAUGHING]
[VICE] But we have
a house blessing tonight.
How could we bless our home
if you did not prepare?
We brought some stuff!
I brought sugar.
[VICE] Right, we need sugar
in our new home
because it will bring good luck
and levity in our home.
- Ayan.
- [TETAY] We have sugar, rice...
- Okay, rice!
- We also have salt.
[VICE] We need to have rice
and salt as we enter the house.
- There we go.
- It's all in there.
And of course,
we also have coins!
- [TETAY AND VERNA] Yes!
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
[TETAY] Catch them
for good luck!
We have coins.
- Whoo!
- And, of course, the coins...
can be donated to our neighbors
- or you can catch them!
- Hey! [LAUGHS]
That will hurt, Meme!
Some neighbors just attend
house blessings to catch coins.
- [LAUGHING]
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
How was your throw like?
Yes! See that?
It's like you're shooting
using a bamboo gun.
- Just like that.
- Hey, catch it for good luck!
It's good luck
but wait a minute!
How embarrassing.
Our neighbors are already here.
But you haven't fixed up
the furniture yet.
Fix up the furniture!
These brats!
[TETAY] Let's just be grateful
that we even have furniture.
[VICE] Why did you even
have to wear that?
- Don't you have a uniform here?
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
Girl, I might just return you
to your agency.
You should be thankful
because...
you're the only one we hired
from the Stinky Agency.
[COMICAL SFX]
- Let's fix this up.
- What should we do?
[BUBBLE WRAP POPPING]
- She's not a garbage bag!
- Oh, sorry.
Oh, you look beautiful
like that.
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
- Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh, it's Lotus Feet!
[LAUGHTER SFX]
[VICE] And where should
we put this?
There, perfect!
Fix those up.
It's embarrassing.
I didn't know that it's just
easy to arrange furniture.
Furnitures in new homes
should be well-arranged.
Some people even hire interior
designers for their homes.
But we're doing it ourselves.
Well, you just need
to push things around.
- There we go.
- Okay.
There we go.
We're all done now.
[TETAY] Yehey!
But we don't have
any guests yet.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
Our efforts would go to waste
if we wouldn't have any guests.
[TETAY] Would you be all right
if we had no guests?
[VICE YELPS]
We cannot have no guests.
- You startled me.
- Yeah.
It seems like you've had
a lot of coffee, huh?
- What a clumsy gay man.
- Yes.
Of course, we can't have
no guests around.
Our Kapamilya and Kapuso viewers
waited so long for this.
Of course,
we can't let that happen.
We cannot let our first episode
not have an explosive guest.
[TETAY] That's right.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
Since we're on GMA now...
our first guest has
to be a Kapuso.
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING, CHEERING]
[TETAY] Our neighbors
seem very excited.
You haven't said a thing yet
but they're already screaming.
- Who could it be?
- Where's my phone?
[VICE] I'm going
to pick a guest...
from my contact list who
I can call over here.
[YELPS] Someone texted me.
- You haven't called one yet?
- Someone texted me.
- NDRRMC. Oh gosh!
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
I always feel worried when
I receive their text.
Okay, which Kapuso in my contact
list seems fun to talk to?
Oh, here it is!
[GASPS] Oh!
[VERNA] Oh!
Let's call him first.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
He doesn't seem
to have mobile data.
[VERNA CHUCKLES]
Hello?
Please come here.
I want to talk to you.
- [VERNA] Oh my.
- [TETAY] Is that your guest?
[ALDEN] Hello? Hello?
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING, CHEERING]
[ALDEN] Hello, guys.
Wait a minute.
I haven't pressed dial yet,
- but someone's talking already.
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
You know, GGV has been high tech
when we moved to GMA.
With how strong the signal
is from their radio tower,
even when you're just
holding your phone,
the person you're about
to contact
already knows
you're going to call them.
- Oh, right.
- Right?
But I texted someone
to hurry up and come here
because I wanted to talk to her.
- Do you know who I texted?
- [VERNA] Who was it?
It's Annette herself.
- [LAUGHING]
- Kidding! I'm just kidding.
[VICE] It's not Miss Annette.
It's this one.
- Where is he?
- I heard him say "Hello."
Maybe, there were
some crossed lines.
- Huh? Crossed lines?
- Crossed lines?
Ah, here we go.
Let's give him a call.
[PLAYFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
- Who could it be?
- What happened?
You know, is that
really your phone?
You can afford a new home,
but not a new phone?
My gosh!
Ah, there it is.
Would you like me to
put the call on speaker?
[AUDIENCE] Yes!
Or should I connect it
through Bluetooth?
[LAUGHTER SFX]
And when I connect it,
you'll hear,
"The Bluetooth device
is connected."
There, here we go!
[LINE RINGING]
[TETAY] Oh, it's ringing.
[ALDEN] Hello?
[AUDIENCE CHEERING, SQUEALING]
[ALDEN] Hello, Vice!
Hello?
[ALDEN] Yes, hello?
Um, sorry, it's a bit noisy
in my house
because I'm having
a house blessing.
So I have a lot of visitors
who came here,
but there's not a lot of
attractive people among them.
[LAUGHTER SFX]
So I am looking for
a handsome visitor.
Um, hello?
- [ALDEN] Hello? Ah...
- Where are you?
[ALDEN] I think
I'm available today.
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
Oh my god!
It's just that I have a new home
and I wanted to show it to you.
[ALDEN] Is that so?
I like that. I really do.
But where are you right now?
[ALDEN] I'm just
around the area.
- Ah.
- Should I come there?
- What did you say?
- It's up to you.
- [AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
[LAUGHING, CHEERING]
- [TETAY] You sound so demure!
- [VERNA] How was it again?
[ALDEN] But it seems like
there's a lot of people there.
I don't want to be a bother.
What did you say?
[ALDEN] It seems like
there's a lot of people
I don't want to be a bother.
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING, SQUEALING]
- Oh no!
Don't mind them.
Those were just the dogs.
They'll be asleep already
by 10:30PM.
[VICE] Um, you can come--
So, will you be here soon?
[ALDEN] Yes, I think
I'll be there in five minutes.
- Ah!
- [VERNA] Whoa!
Oh, you're quick.
You'll just take five minutes.
I last for quite a long time.
- [VERNA CHUCKLES]
- [ALDEN] I'll be there soon.
- [DOORBELL RINGING]
- [VICE GASPS]
Wait a second,
someone's ringing the doorbell.
- [DOORBELL RINGING]
- Hello?
I think our call ended
all of a sudden.
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
[VICE] Wait a minute.
By the way you look, shouldn't
you be the one opening the door?
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
- Fine, I'll open the door.
Our furniture is new,
so don't sit on it like that!
Maybe it's the water delivery.
Hurry up.
- Who is it? How impatient!
- Who could it be?
Who? What?
- How do we even open the door?
- [TETAY] Just push it.
- [TETAY GASPS]
- [VERNA EXCLAIMS]
Oh my god! He's finally here!
Gandang Gabi Vice!
Hello, everyone!
My friend here is
so easy to talk to!
- [VERNA] He's already here!
- [TETAY EXCLAIMS]
My god, Alden!
Gosh, how rowdy!
[LAUGHTER SFX]
[AUDIENCE CHANTING]
Alden! Alden!
What a surprise, right?
- Hello, everyone!
- [TETAY] Fantastic!
- Good evening to you all!
- How explosive!
- Gandang Gabi, Alden!
- Gandang Gabi, everyone!
[ALDEN] Here, I brought a gift.
That's how quickly
I get prepared.
From our phone call, I was able
to buy a housewarming gift,
and I was able to get here
right away.
You're truly a good friend!
He really is a reliable friend.
Anytime you call him,
he is available.
- He's always there.
- He won't say no to you.
[VICE] They're my housemates.
That's Tetay and that's...
That's our newly-bought
pit bull.
[LAUGHTER SFX]
[VICE] Verna, meet Alden.
People may not know it,
but I'm a big fan of Verna.
- Ooh!
- Yes!
I'm not kidding,
I watch her on Showtime.
On Muse...
What's your segment again?
- Breaking Muse.
- Breaking Muse!
That time when you were
judging Jessy Mendiola.
I don't know what to feel
about it, but you were great!
And you also sang Chandelier
but you were the chandelier.
And I just found out
recently that...
we had a mutual friend from
where she used to live at.
- And she knew...
- [VICE] Who was it?
- It's Michael Bristol.
- Yeah.
She also knows my executive
assistant, Mama Ten.
We really have a lot of
mutual friends because
the truth is
you're my second cousin.
Ouch, I thought
it was something else.
Second cousin?
So your mother took pills but
you were still conceived, huh?
- [CHUCKLING]
- [LAUGHTER SFX]
But yeah,
he's a big fan of yours.
You know, when you were
on Showtime, he would text me
to let me tell you that
he's a huge fan of yours.
- Ohh!
- Yes, it's true.
It's because he likes
buying puppies at Tiendesitas.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[VICE] And because I knew
that you would meet here,
I had Berna groomed
just for you.
- That's why my skin got better.
- [TETAY] Right!
She was even biting me earlier.
I had to tell her that
we had a visitor!
But Vice, Verna, and Tetay,
thank you.
- This is a rare opportunity.
- [ALL CHEERING, APPLAUDING]
I feel honored and excited
to be here.
Even back when Kris
and Mai were interviewing me
over the phone for prep,
I couldn't contain
my excitement already.
I finished the interview myself.
I told them, "Ask me anything
you want to ask me, go!"
[SQUEALING]
- Let's go!
- Period!
I am so excited,
everyone is so excited!
This is our first--
Alden and I have known
each other for a long time
but all we do
is have small talks.
This is the first time
I'll be interviewing him.
- [ALDEN] Yes, yes.
- To have a proper conversation
with him on my program.
You'll be able to watch him
and I in one whole episode.
I am so excited so,
are you all ready?
[AUDIENCE] Yes!
Let the fun begin
as we return here in...
What was our tagline before?
The most... what?
- [STAFF SHOUTING]
- Every Sunday night? Okay.
Okay.
- I've already forgotten it.
- [LAUGHTER]
It's been six years.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[STAFF SHOUTING]
Alden's excited, so am I,
and so are all of you!
- [VERNA] Yay!
- That's why let's start
the fun and gossiping
after the break
here at the most fun
and most addicting show
every Sunday night this is...
[ALL] Gandang Gabi, Vice!
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[AUDIENCE CHEERING, APPLAUDING]
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING, LAUGHING]
[ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING]
"Hi, Alden!"
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING, GIGGLING]
"I miss you, Vice."
[AUDIENCE SQUEALS, LAUGHING]
[AUDIENCE MEMBER] I miss you,
Vice.
[ROMANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
"You're so handsome!"
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING, GIGGLES]
[ROMANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
"It feels so good..."
- [VICE GAGGING]
- [AUDIENCE SQUEALING, LAUGHING]
"... to love you."
- [VICE GIGGLES MANIACALLY]
- [LAUGHTER]
[ROMANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
"I can't seem to look you...
in the...
- eye."
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
[APPLAUDING]
[ROMANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING, APPLAUDING]
"You can give it...
- a try."
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING, LAUGHING]
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
[ROMANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[AUDIENCE SQUEALS]
Playing as AlDub is so
heart throbbing, huh?
- [LAUGHTER]
- Right?
- Playing as AlDub!
- I miss it!
It brings a lot of memories
as well.
It's been so long. It was...
2016. 10 years ago,
- a decade ago.
- Wow!
It's so easy for you to say
that you miss it,
that it brings back
so much memories.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- [LAUGH TRACK]
As for us, we want to forget
those memories!
The nerve to say those words
in my face!
[MOCKINGLY] Such good times!
Brings back so much memories!
Wow! You guys had a blast, huh?
- [SILLY SFX]
- Hold up, hold up!
Do you think our team was happy
when AlDub was a thing?
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- [SUSPENSEFUL STING]
I'm so sorry. I didn't mean it
that way.
- But...
- No! You really
slapped in our faces
that you guys were happy
while we were in deep sorrow!
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
Director, just please cut
that part out. [LAUGHS]
[VICE] But that was really
phenomenal.
- AlDub is phenomenal.
- [ALDEN] Yes.
- That...
- [AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
That was one of the greatest
moments
in Philippine television. Right?
Um, we were just so grateful
with that journey.
Us hosts at Eat Bulaga and
of course, Maine Mendoza too.
And uh, we...
How do I put it? We didn't
mean to... somehow?
- It wasn't planned.
-[VICE] You didn't mean to what?
Ow! My head hurts.
How do I explain this
to a lawyer? [PANTS]
- [SILLY SFX]
- You didn't mean to put us
- in danger?
- [LAUGHTER]
Goodness, my career has just
started back then.
But it felt like I could go back
to sewing rags at any moment.
- [LAUGHTER]
- My god.
I'm sorry, Vice.
[SINGSONG] While you're basking
in joy,
we were wallowing in sorrow.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- Goodness me.
You guys were really happy
then, huh?
- Well...
- Your ratings were higher, huh?
[LAUGHTER]
- [ALDEN] Kind of, kind of.
- Yeah.
Every episode at Eat Bulaga
must be a feast, a celebration.
While for us, every episode,
we get called to the 15th floor.
[SILLY SFX]
How do I respond to that?
[LAUGHING]
- [VICE] Are you aware?
- [LAUGHS]
- About what?
- [VICE] That...
That you guys dog walked us.
I have a-- Here, Vice.
I have a question that maybe
you could prove to be false.
- If you could.
- [VICE] Oh, you know me.
I don't ever cover any truth
in my life.
[ALDEN] Sheesh!
The memo.
- What memo?
- That you can't watch
when AlDub is on...
- is it true or not?
- Oh, you!
There was no memo like that.
It was just an email.
[LAUGHTER]
- [MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING]
- [AUDIENCE HOLLERING]
Because usually, memos
are written and passed around.
It was an email.
- An email.
- Yes.
- I see.
- Right.
It says no one should watch
AlDub.
Come on, we only have each other
and we'll still have the guts
to support AlDub?
Isn't it only right for us
not to watch AlDub?
It's like 99.9%
of the Philippines
is an AlDub supporter.
Even Safeguard's soap
got nothing on you.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
The 0.1% left was us.
But Vice, to be fair,
during that time,
it was just an, um...
I don't know, I've probably
talked about this before.
About how it began.
- It was not planned at all.
- [VICE] Just whose idea was it?
-It was the creative directors.
- [VICE] Who?
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- Should I name them?
Where's that bastard?
Screw them!
[ALDEN] Woah! Dang!
For real. We shed real tears.
-I'll tell you their name later.
- Please do.
- And their phone too.
- [LAUGHING]
Since there's no Eat Bulaga
anymore, maybe we can hire them.
[LAUGHTER]
"Hey, maybe you can cook up
something for us."
[SILLY SFX]
[ALDEN] It was like...
Yeah so, Maine started
at the barangay
and then, for a time,
she still hasn't...
I think she appeared once
or twice
at the barangay already.
I was at the studio
at that time.
I hosted segments at Eat Bulaga
and then I was taking my break
'cause it's time for
Juan for All, All for Juan.
So it was Tito, Vic and Joey
sitting at the panel.
That's the main body
of the show.
I was having my lunch
then all of a sudden,
the floor director called me
and said,
"'Den, just sit there
at the front
- [VICE] Mm-hmm.
- and watch the...
- The segment.
- Juan for All, All for Juan."
I was like, "Sure thing!"
So I finished my meal quickly
and sat there and then...
um...
In all honestly, Maine was so...
entertaining to watch when
she was doing Dubsmash.
- It wasn't TikTok yet.
- Yes, she was so popular.
She was the most popular
Dubsmash maker back then.
[ALDEN] Yes! So I was like...
When, uh, during that time,
she wasn't talking at all.
- So, the--
- Who thought of the idea
to not let her speak?
Because if only she spoke
right away...
- [LAUGHTER]
- [SILLY SFX]
There would've been no AlDub.
[ALDEN] Should I expose them?
Why did you not let her speak?
- [LAUGHING] I need to--
- [VICE LAUGHS]
- [VICE] And then?
- So, yeah!
Because, get this.
On It's Showtime, I yap nonstop.
Blah, blah, blah!
Yet I was getting obliterated by
someone who doesn't talk at all!
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- Isn't it heartbreaking?
And then when you saw
that she wasn't talking,
I didn't know that...
the camera was panned towards me
while she was doing Dubsmash.
I was just looking at her
like this
and I was having fun
while watching her.
And then the director
showed it on screen.
[VICE] Then your reaction
was seen.
They saw my reaction,
and she saw it too.
- And then that mere reaction
- [VICE] Yes.
started everything.
You were just watching her,
all happy and entertained
by her antics.
- [ALDEN] Yes.
- Then she found out,
- she acted shy and flustered.
- Yes, yes.
And that started the magic.
Everything, yes. That was how.
That started the magic
at Eat Bulaga.
- That started the curse.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- In It's Showtime.
- I resign, I resign.
I resign. Lord, sorry, Lord!
[VICE] Right. For them,
it was just a natural occurence.
[ALDEN] Save me, guys...
For us, it was like...
a calamity that the NDRRMC
failed to warn us about.
- [LAUGH TRACK]
- We weren't ready. Like,
what? The typhoon is here
already?! We had no idea.
And it was a super typhoon
to boot!
That's why you took
the entire nation by storm.
[VERNA] Woah!
That's why it's called
AlDub Nation, right?
The Philippines became
an AlDub Nation.
But it was truly entertaining.
- [ALDEN] Thank you, thank you.
- I peek at it sometimes.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [LAUGH TRACK]
Of course I had to watch it
to know what is going on.
Right? What is going on?
Why are they such a hit?
So I explained,
"It's fun. This and that
is happening."
And then I pray everyday,
"Lord, please make this happen."
[LAUGHTER]
But it was really amazing.
But were you guys aware
of what was happening to us?
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
We are.
So where's your conscience?
- [ALDEN] It was...
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[TETAY] That's right.
- [LAUGHTER]
-[ AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
- [VICE] Right?
- That's right!
That's why I haven't forgotten
what Miss Annette said
when we had a meeting.
She said, "What's good
about collaborations?"
She said, "It's a win-win
situation."
It doesn't always have to be
a winner and then a loser.
Miss Annette said,
"As a Christian,
it doesn't make us happy
if we win while someone loses
when we could all win."
So why didn't you guys
apply that?
[VICE] We were knocked out.
[TETAY] Answer, Alden!
Save me. Nelson Canlas!
- Please, Nelson Canlas.
- That Nelson Canlas too.
That's right. He reports
your news every night!
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
- It's all about AlDub!
- [LAUGHTER]
No but, when I watched it
I thought,
"This is really magical."
It was so fun to watch.
Really entertaining.
It was really an escape, right?
When you watch it, you'll really
forget what you're doing,
your problems,
what you're going through,
because you'll tune in to it
no matter what.
- And I was so mad at the...
- The granny?
- Yes, at Granny Nidora.
- Yeah.
At JoWaPao. I was infuriated!
Because they were so good!
I thought that they were
really funny.
Then I talked to Vhong Navarro
and Jhong Hilario.
- "Vhong...
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
can you put a bow on your head?"
[LAUGHTER]
Oh, and let me share
this too, Vice.
During that time when we
were doing everything,
until after Tamang Panahon,
we didn't have a script.
- [VICE] I know!
- We had no script at all.
Basically, we'll just play along
with the scenario
on where we left off
- the episode before.
- Alright then, big shots!
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- [ALDEN] I was just explaining.
I was just explaining things.
- [TETAY] Do that face again.
- Okay, sorry.
- [ALDEN] I was just joking.
- [TETAY LAUGHING]
Because while he was recalling
happy memories,
- [TETAY] Yes.
- I was recalling the sad ones.
- [VERNA] The sadness!
- Right? For him they were happy
- while for me, it's traumatic.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
Plus we're reminiscing
at the same time. Okay.
As you were saying.
There was no script and um...
we were just waiting
for instructions
through our in-ear monitors
and it was live.
- [VICE] So you had in-ears.
- We did.
- You'll hear instructions?
- Yes, yes.
Oh, okay because
at It's Showtime we don't.
- [ALDEN] Period!
- [TETAY] Woah!
[VERNA] Yes!
That's why see? Our ratings
were so low.
Our ratings were so low!
My god! We should've used
in-ears!
- [LAUGHTER]
- So that's why!
- [TETAY] It's cheap too!
- We should've used in-ears.
If I'm not mistaken,
there was an episode
where your ratings
were above 40%
and our ratings were 5% or 4%.
Yeah. Can I see
your reaction again?
I had no idea.
The gap was that huge.
And that time,
while you were waiting
for directions
through your in-ear,
I was waiting for the management
to call me
and tell me that the show
will be canceled.
I swear.
I was ready for it.
- [TETAY] For real.
- [VERNA] Aww...
I swear.
It was one of the darkest,
heaviest, saddest,
no kidding, saddest stages
of It's Showtime
as well as me as an entertainer.
It was really hard to bear
but it was also one of the
things I'm thankful for.
I learned a lot of things.
That experience we had,
made our program stronger.
Like what we said,
we have nothing
to be scared of now.
AlDub already happened,
is there anything
bigger than them?
If we were able
to get through it,
then we can go through anything.
AlDub was so huge.
Alden, Maine.
You know, there was one time
when I went home in Tambunting.
Because back then, I visit home
every now and then
and give away a little something
and stuff.
Hanging out with them.
One time, after I got out
of my car,
the kids were chanting,
"AlDub! AlDub!"
- I swear.
- [AUDIENCE EXCLAIMING]
I went to the bathroom
and cried a little.
I was like...
mind you, this is my turf
but they're still chanting
for AlDub.
So I said, you can't really
explain this.
This country loves them so much.
- [AUDIENCE APPLAUDING]
-[VICE] So I told It's Showtime
that I was actually mad at them.
Because of them,
I couldn't watch AlDub
regularly.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- I'm always behind.
I just ask people for updates.
It's Showtime was such
a hindrance!
- Adjust its time slot!
- [ALDEN LAUGHING]
I couldn't watch Alden
and Maine.
It was crazy. But,
I told this to It's Showtime.
The Philippines is so lucky
to have experienced AlDub
in this lifetime.
- [ALDEN] Thank you, Vice.
- Right? It's different.
It was a phenomenon.
It was just so fun, right?
You guys made so many people
happy.
After all, that's our role
as entertainers, right?
To give our fellow countrymen
a moment to escape
from, of course,
their daily lives
especially those
who are underprivileged.
It's like their only way
to forget...
- what's happening.
- Yeah, and it gave hope.
You gave them hope.
Right? Just like in the story,
those stories are effective.
The fairy tale-like ones.
Like, a man who is so handsome
like a prince charming
with a girl who's simple
and humble,
a Cinderella story, right?
Where they'll think,
"Oh, so there's hope.
I don't need to be fair-skinned
for someone to fall for me
and look at me.
I don't need to be immediately
popular
for a popular person
to pay attention to me."
You guys gave people hope
that such a thing is possible.
And it's important that as you
watch a noontime show,
you feel hopeful.
- Right?
- That's right, Vice.
[VICE] But, again...
- [LAUGHTER]
- Get him!
[VICE SIGHS HEAVILY]
Why are you guys
just laughing over there?
Because you've really hurt him!
[VICE] Exactly. You've mentioned
about the memo, right?
Right?
I also have a memo for the gays.
[TETAY] What is, sis? [WHEEZES]
Don't post about AlDub
on social media.
Because even on social media,
on FaceBook, Twitter,
they're all over it!
- Right?
- Hey, Nelson Canlas!
You're the one who report
about it!
Do you guys know
that he's depressed?
He won't even get up to eat!
- Right, Tetay?
- Yes! We went to his place,
you have no idea!
"Vice, let's eat.", "Later.
Just stay with me for now."
It was that bad, Alden!
- [ALDEN] Hold your horses.
- And you don't know about it.
Wait, what about us?
It's our sister! He couldn't
even eat! You're so insensitive!
My baby wouldn't even eat!
- I said sorry!
- Now you come here
just to revisit those memories?
- [TETAY] That's right!
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- [ALDEN] Uh-oh...
- You're so cruel, Alden.
- [ALDEN] Ow.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- Apologize to our sister!
- No.
- We're good now.
- [TETAY] Oh, okay. Sorry.
I never took it personally.
Even before. Every time
we saw each other
during events, I'm not lying,
Alden is really kind.
- Really kind!
- No matter where we meet,
I'm even the one
who's a little awkward.
- [TETAY] It's like that, huh?
- Because of course,
since it's a competition,
people often think
that there's tension.
Like, "Oh, it's Vice and Alden!"
when they see us together.
Alden would be the one to run
while shouting, "Miss Vice!"
He's very kind, smells good,
and so handsome.
- [VERNA] Wow!
- [TETAY] Very polite.
- [VERNA] True!
- [VICE] So every time we meet
and I see Alden, we'll be
greeting each other.
"Alden, hi! Hi!"
- [LAUGHTER]
- [SILLY SFX]
Alden and I are all good.
That's why he shouldn't
apologize to me.
But I will give you one chance.
Apologize
to the Madlang people.
[LAUGHTER]
- Um...
- [VICE] You've really hurt us.
Um... [CLEARS THROAT]
Where's the camera? Is it this?
Ah, so...
To the Madlang People,
to the people behind Showtime--
- Let's pretend this is in 2016.
- Sure.
You really want to take me
back to that year, huh?
[LAUGHTER]
That was 10 years ago,
but it still hurts.
[SILLY SFX, LAUGH TRACK PLAYING]
To the hosts of It's Showtime,
most especially
to Miss Vice Ganda,
I'd like to apologize for
whatever wrong we've done.
If we did something out
of pure intentions, but--
As you said earlier, Vice,
we have only one intention,
and that is
to make people happy.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING, APPLAUDING]
But still,
I'd like to apologize because
I know how heavy it is.
I honestly don't know
if you're joking around
or being serious.
C'mon, I'm being serious here.
- [ALDEN] Ah, really?
- [LAUGHS]
No, I'm just messing around.
- [TETAY] No, this is for Vice.
- What is this for?
They said
you were about to cry.
Didn't I tell you
I'd call if I needed you?!
[VERNA] You're about
to cry, Meme.
See, we're just
concerned for you.
We love you, Vice.
Yeah, but...
- I am very grateful to Alden--
- [ALDEN] Can I just say,
I won't forget the first
surreal moment where
it was my first time being
a guest on It's Showtime.
Before you introduced us,
you said something--
I think it was a promotion
for Family of Two,
I was with Sharon Cuneta.
Ah.
It seemed strange, this is--
This is something
we never expected.
When I heard the words
you were saying,
that's when I realized,
"Wow, who would've thought
that after all these years
and after all that happened,
we'd end up being here together
with one goal in the industry."
And all those times,
we were okay!
We were all fine.
Our shows just aired at the same
time, and during those times
our fans and supporters
were at each other's throats.
But
Eat Bulaga! and It's Showtime
have always been okay.
We don't have any bad blood.
They were kind to us.
That's why we don't have
anything bad to say about them.
- Right? That's why
- Yes, Vice.
Whenever I see you, my aura
feels natural and sincere.
My face lights up
whenever I see Alden.
Also, Alden just
looks very handsome.
- [TETAY] It's true.
- [VERNA] It's true.
[VICE] Especially now--
Now you're both acting
fine around me!
No, what Vice said was true,
you are handsome!
[ALDEN] You were both
so heartless with me earlier!
[TETAY] You were in
the wrong earlier.
[ALDEN] Son of a--
Okay, okay, sorry!
- He got mad!
-[VICE] We're fine now.
[ALDEN] Sorry, sorry, Vice.
I told him earlier
that he looked
younger because he lost weight!
You look handsome.
Are-- are you eating well?
- I am.
- [VICE] Are you tired?
You look like you've
lost some weight.
As i said in an interview
with Nelson Canlas--
since he's there,
I'm calling him out.
Now that I'm reaching
my mid-30s, going late 30s,
I'm also having a
slightly different perspective
on how I take on life.
The others are saying that
I'm still young, but for me,
the earlier, the better.
Right now, I'm a little
more intentional
with the things
I let in my life.
The number one thing,
of course, is what I eat.
- What do you eat now?
- My lifestyle.
Everything but in moderation.
- So, everything?
- Yes, I still eat those.
Don't the others shift
to being vegan?
[ALDEN] Yeah.
I take everything in moderation,
I also have a healthy
lifestyle, and I exercise.
Most especially a positive
outlook on life.
- Yes. That's important.
- Yes.
We're reducing
toxic people in our lives.
- That's true.
- [VERNA] True.
[VICE] That's true, right?
No matter what checkup
you do, multivitamins you take,
or suppliments you take,
if you're being surrounded
with too much negativity,
you'll be consumed by it,
and you'll get sick.
I'm all for that, 100%.
I actually feel shy.
You brought me wine, right?
- Yes, wine.
- You even brought me wine,
butwe don't have anything
to give you in return.
We have something here, Meme.
- [VICE] What food?
- Wait, let me heat her up.
- [LAUGHS] No, not me!
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- We did some research, Meme.
- [VICE] Well, what is it?
We found out what
Alden's favorite food is.
- So, what is it?
- [VERNA] Yes.
Because I believe...
that a way to a man's heart
is through his stomach.
- Wow.
- Did you say stomach?
- Stomach!
- [ALDEN] Ah, stomach!
- [VICE IMITATES VERNA]
- Enough, girl!
You're so--
Wait, what is that?
[TETAY] We prepared spaghetti.
- Alden is very picky.
- [VICE] Is that what I saw
earlier?
The one in the plastic?
- [LAUGHTER]
- Did you cut open the end?
I actually saw Verna
eating it earlier.
We bought it from
a breakfast buffet, actually.
Don't say that in front of
our guest. It's embarrassing.
- Is that all?
- [TETAY] No, of course not.
- Come here and eat, Alden.
- Alden loves--
[VICE] You should go
there and eat, Alden.
[ALDEN] What?
That looks good. Wow.
Wait.
Where did this food come from?
Where-- Ah, Verna!
Someone will eat. Stay away.
- Wait, where is the...
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- I'll go with you, Meme.
- What do you need?
Where's the lime and ketchup?
Oh, you need lime?
- Here's the lime.
- It's right there.
- Lime?
- Yes.
- Yes, and...
- Wow.
Lime...
- Here you go.
- This is embarrassing.
You were so against me earlier,
now you're serving me.
C'mon...
What's the lime for?
For the noodles?
- For the noodles.
- No, for the spaghetti.
- Hey!
- What?!
What?!
You add lime to your spaghetti?
- Why?!
- Yes.
This is my weird
food combination.
Actually,
it's not just spaghetti.
I love--
- Will you taste it?
- Yes.
- Let me add it first.
- You taste it first.
We don't have forks
so we should share--
[ALDEN] Yeah, sure! Go ahead!
No, uh...
Actually, Verna uses
her hands to eat spaghetti.
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- It's true.
She also uses a toothpick
when she eats noodles.
That's our finger food.
Noodles.
Okay, so...
I love bending the usual
flavor of the food I eat.
Do you wanna bend her neck too?
- [LAUGHTER]
- Please, don't.
Then I'll put ketchup.
Just kidding.
- Then, um...
- Do you eat
Sinigang with her head.
- [LAUGHTER]
- With the salmon's head.
[LAUGHS] I'm just kidding!
- Are you serious? With lime?
- Yes!
We're so used to spaghetti
cooked in Filipino style.
- My supporters get this.
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
You guys know too much.
Yeah, this weird food combo.
Unlike the typical way,
I eat spaghetti with lime.
This is my childhood.
When I was a kid,
this was what I liked to eat.
Who influenced this?
Who started this?
- Me.
- Who influenced you to do this?
It was just me.
I really like sour food.
Then I thought about how
Filipino spaghetti is sweet,
So, why not--
I actually like lime.
It's sweet and sour,
so that's the combo.
Why don't we add groupers to
it if you want sweet and sour?
How does it taste?
- Don't speak in English.
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
Speaking in Kapampangan
doesn't suit you as well.
- It's good.
- Is it?
Not that.
- That's my brush.
- [LAUGHTER]
- That's for the spaghetti!
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[TETAY] That's
for the spaghetti!
[VICE] Wait! There's
sauce in it! Oh my God!
- I thought it was clean!
- [TETAY] It's clean!
- [VERNA LAUGHS]
- There's sauce!
You used it as a hairbrush!
- [LAUGH TRACK PLAYING]
- Aw.
Aw!
- Aw!
- [MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING]
- You look like a Tamagotchi.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
- The virtual pet from before.
Meme is acting like that,
but she's secretly swooning.
- Who?
- [TETAY] You!
- But...
- I'm already married.
- Ion and I are friends.
- They're actually friends.
We play basketball together.
Who wouldn't swoon
when it comes to Alden?
It's Alden Richards
- Jose Rizal didn't swoon.
- [LAUGHTER]
He wasn't there!
Do you really think
Jose Rizal would swoon?!
- Taste the spaghetti!
- Just taste the spaghetti!
- I'll taste it.
- Yeah, sure.
It's not that different
since we have sour pastas.
How much lime do you put?
There's only two there, Vice.
- But it tastes fine.
- [VERNA] Does it taste good?
[LAUGHTER]
- Does it taste weird?
- What do you think, Meme?
- [TETAY] Here you go, Verna.
- [ALDEN] Weird?
- You know what...
- [TETAY] Be honest.
Alden is such a good sport.
He's so down to earth.
But the spaghetti
is just so cold.
[LAUGHTER]
Why is this so cold?!
There's ice cream underneath!
- You didn't say anything.
- It was the ice creams fault.
Okay, let's--
Even without the lime,
it's already sour!
- I think it's spoiled.
- It's already spoiled.
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- Is this not Italian pasta?
What's funny
is that Alden ate a lot,
and he acted like it was good.
He's such a commercial model.
- [LAUGHS] I stuck with it.
- He's such an endorser.
- Endorser.
- [LAUGH TRACK PLAYING]
- Okay.
- There's one more thing.
What else do you need?
- Ketchup.
- For spaghetti too?
No, for noodles!
- But--
- Why put it with noodles?
I discovered this
when I was young too.
I was a bit of a--
You discovered a lot of things
as a kid. Are you a scientist?
- [LAUGHTER]
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- [VERNA] He's a smart kid.
- I likes watching Sineskwela.
So...
I first discovered putting
ketchup in noodles
before I found out
that in San Pedro--
I grew up in Santa Rosa.
See? That's why
I think we're meant to be.
- I live in Parañaque. [LAUGHS]
- Oh, sorry.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[VICE] What's funny is
you're being picky!
[LAUGHTER]
How dare you? You rejected him.
You could've just pretended!
He even held your hand!
- Yeah.
- You should've just agreed!
He even held your hand!
He doesn't just touch anyone's
hand, but he held yours!
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
Fine, let's do it again.
I'm from Santa Rosa, so
I really think it's meant to be.
- Yeah.
- What--
It's a shame
I got married early.
- Ah, really?
- Goodness.
- See?
- Your hands are so small.
- [ALDEN LAUGHS]
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
You want some ketchup?
- Give it to him.
- [TETAY] There's none.
Oh, wait.
- Do we have ketchup?
- We don't have it?
I bought one earlier!
Maybe the neighbors stole it!
Where's our ketchup?
Who stole it?!
I know you guys have it!
[TETAY] Find it, Meme.
Where's our ketchup?
[VERNA] Where is it?
I know you.
[ALDEN] The one wearing red,
maybe he knows where it is.
- Who? Him?
- Yeah.
[VICE] Where's the ketchup?
- [ALDEN] Take it out, boss.
- Did you take it?
Earlier, you were wearing
white. Now it's red.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [ALDEN] Oh no.
I think it's here!
Oh no. Oh no.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
- [VERNA] Is that it?
- I think this is the ketchup.
- [LAUGHTER]
- Why?!
Well, it's in the label.
- Read it.
- [LAUGHTER]
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[VERNA LAUGHS] This is ketchup.
You even look so Christian!
- C'mon, Crissy!
- You stole--
- Do you know her? Is she a fan?
- I know her!
Crissy, you're making
a mess here on GGV!
- Son of a--
- That's crazy.
Are you not
embarrassed for Alden?
- I'm so sorry.
- [ALDEN] C'mon, Crissy!
- I didn't teach that to you.
- The ketchup looked good.
[TETAY] Maybe
she'll take it home.
Stand up.
Look at how she's dressed.
You look like a member
of Couples for Christ.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
But you stole
your neighbor's ketchup!
You look like you pray a lot,
but you're here stealing.
Also, this ketchup...
This is how you eat it.
- [LAUGHTER]
- Wait, is it like this?
[VERNA] Wait, no!
Don't do that!
It looks like a baby bottle.
- Give it to Alden!
- [PLAYFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
Send this woman to jail.
Wow, he's such a gentleman.
[VERNA] Wow!
- [TETAY] You're so dramatic.
- [VERNA LAUGHS]
[LAUGHTER]
[VICE] It's like I have gout.
I'm so sorry,
I actually have gout.
Meme Vice isn't joking.
That's actually true.
- [LAUGHTER]
- Hey!
Between us, let's see
who's walking properly.
- [LAUGHTER]
- So, how much ketchup--
Oh no, I apologize if it's cold.
If I had to choose any
condiment, I'd pick ketchup.
I put ketchup
on top of ketchup.
- Ketchup on everything.
- [VICE] Oh!
- You put ketchup on everything?
- Yes.
Why don't you put
ketchup on your banana?
Why not?
Yes, that's good.
I put ketchup not only on
noodles but also on mung beans.
Ketchup on sinigang.
Are you okay, Alden?
[VERNA] Is it true?
Are you that weird?
Do your relatives
at home not scold you?
They don't taste it.
I eat it.
- Ketchup on mung beans?
- [TETAY] Alden loves to eat--
[VERNA] Look
at him drizzling it!
I am not kidding,
this is how I eat.
It's like you're adding
ketchup on pizza!
[LAUGHTER]
Hmm.
- [VERNA] Hey.
- [VICE] He's like an endorser.
- What?
- No, it's hot!
What do you mean it's hot?
Oh, this one's hot.
The other one's not.
[VICE] Let me try.
Ketchup.
Delicious.
Get noodles and
add ketchup on top of it.
Don't put too much.
Just add a bit.
- So you won't be surprised.
- [TETAY] Isn't that too much?
- You might be surprised.
- [VERNA] That's a lot.
I actually haven't eaten yet.
[VERNA] You should
ask us, Alden.
- [ALDEN] What?
- You should ask us to eat.
- Let's eat later.
- [TETAY] Look at Vice!
[SCREAMS]
Didn't I tell you to stay away
from me when I eat?
[SILLY SFX, LAUGH TRACK PLAYING]
[VERNA] Rate it.
- Oh!
- Hmm.
[LAUGHTER]
- You're such a liar.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
- He was lying?!
[UPBEAT MUSIC CONTINUES]
- You're such a liar, Alden.
- [ALDEN] Are you serious?
It's so... It's so weird!
Actually,
everyone in my family, my dad--
my mom when she was alive,
my siblings,
we all love ketchup.
That's why we add
ketchup to our food.
[VICE] Oh no,
Alden is sad now.
- Hey.
- Because of ketchup?
His mom is gone.
I told you to go first!
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHS]
- [MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING]
- Well--
- Don't answer that!
That's enough!
You might gain weight!
You look great!
Wipe your--
- Aw!
- [HEARTFELT MUSIC PLAYING]
- Say "Ah!"
- Ah!
- Here, this is for you.
- Perfect, right?
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[TETAY] Good, isn't it?
The ketchup does taste good.
Hey, that's from Alden.
- Ah!
- [LAUGHS]
[HEARTFELT MUSIC PLAYING]
- Meme!
- At least we shared.
But that came from me!
- [UPBEAT MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [LAUGHTER]
I forgot that
it had your saliva!
I was wondering why
it smells like dog breath!
Let's go back here.
Let's take a seat.
Do you want some water?
Oh yeah, wait.
- Soda?
- We have soda.
You might think it's soda
because it looks like soy sauce.
We also have
low-sugar iced tea.
- He said he wants soda.
- Do we have soda?
Hey, Miss,
can we get two sodas?!
- [LAUGHTER]
- Someone is under here.
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- Look at him!
- The noodles are delicious.
- Hey, Alden!
Alden, you're crazy!
- [LAUGHTER]
- [HEARTFELT MUSIC PLAYING]
[TETAY] You're acting
as if I'll use it, Meme!
[VICE LAUGHS]
That was fun.
[BURPS]
It's delicious.
But...
I prefer the noodles
to the cold spaghetti.
- It's cold spaghetti.
- As if the food is frozen.
[TETAY] I told you there
was ice cream under it.
It's funny. I didn't
expect you to be this bubbly.
- He looks--
- [ALDEN] My fans know this.
He looks like a child
who's scared to be scolded.
He just says hello,
then goes all quiet.
And your face looks so innocent.
You look like a young man
who's always so composed.
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
- [VICE] But...
I asked him earlier
what we should talk about,
he said anything.
Even explicit topics!
- [ALDEN] Yes.
- I was like, whoa.
-[TETAY] You know what, Meme--
- No, because
most of the interviews I did
in the past were very formal.
Sometimes, we talk about
something explicit but,
there's nothing too extreme.
Will we talk about that, Vice?
Why did you expect--
Is that what you think of me?
- [ALDEN] No!
- [TETAY] Do that again.
- [LAUGHTER]
- Is that what you think of me?
[LAUGHTER]
- [ALDEN] No, not really!
- You're too much, Alden.
What color is your underwear?
- [LAUGHS]
- It's black.
I'm just kiddin.
How long have
you been in showbiz?
Uh, going 16. 16 years.
- I started in 2011.
- [VICE] 16?
So, when Showtime started,
that's when you started too?
Showtime is 16 years
old now, going on 17.
You've been in
the industry for 16 years.
What were you doing
when you started?
- I was...
- How old were you?
Before I went to showbiz,
I joined male pageants
in the province.
But the first pageant I joined,
- I studied for one year.
- [VICE] Oh!
Male pageants?
So you had to wear trunks?
- Yes.
- You don't have any pictures?
You should ask them!
[VICE] Why are there no pics
of that on the internet?
- They have some!
- All his pics look wholesome!
Right, guys?
[ALDEN] Yeah, but...
I had pictures like that.
It took a lot of people
to convince me to do that.
- [VICE] Oh.
- For me to do that.
But why did you join?
Is it for money or...
- I was forced to do it.
- Ah.
I was forced to do
the first two.
The first one was for school.
I think it was for Mr.
and Mrs. Intramurals 2008.
- [VICE] Did you win?
- Yes, I immediately won.
It felt good. It felt surreal.
I realized I was good-looking
and I could join these things.
My teacher forced me to do that.
When I went back to Laguna
to finish my studies
for high school in third
and fourth year,
When I graduated, Ginoong
Santa Rosa was in season.
Our town captain
forced me to do that.
- So I had no choice.
- Did you win again?
Yes, it felt good.
I won 70,000 pesos.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah!
That was my first time
having 70,000.
- So the first thing I did--
- That's a lot of money already!
The first thing I did
was go to the bank.
I didn't know what to do.
I just followed my grandma.
I actually grew up
around my grandma, Vice.
She taught me
that every penny counts.
She told me that I should
spend with intention.
When did you begin
working as an actor?
How did you get into acting?
After I joined Ginoong Laguna,
that's when...
- [VICE] Someone discovered you?
- Yes, someone did.
It was Carlites De Guzman.
My fans know him too.
Right?
- [VICE] He was your manager.
- Yes, until now.
- Ah, really?
- Actually, uh...
- We have no contract.
- Oh!
We don't have a contract,
but the recognition and, ah...
everything is mine.
There's no need for papers.
There are a lot of talent
managers like that.
You have an
artist-manager relationship,
but they have no contract
binding them.
But they work together.
There are those who
have a contract binding them,
- but they don't get projects.
- Yes. [LAUGHS]
What is that?
That's what hurts, right?
You don't have a contract
with your manager,
but you have tons of projects.
Others have a contract
with their managers,
you have waited
a long time to sign,
but not a single project
came in for you.
Oh!
- That's true.
- It's painful, right?
Gosh, when am I going to be
free from this?
I signed ages ago, but I still
haven't gotten any projects yet.
- Good for you.
- 20 years.
- No contracts!
- None! But...
One of the things that I admire
about Miss Carlites is
she never showed up here.
GMA knows this.
Carlites has never
set foot in GMA.
Why?
- Uh...
- Is she part of a syndicate?
Why isn't she showing herself?
I'm starting to think that too.
Does she have an estafa case?
Was she a scammer before?
Not like that. Like...
Maybe we're like...
She doesn't make
her presence felt always?
She's not like,
sorry for lack of a better term,
she doesn't like to show-off.
No, she's not like that.
Managers who like to be known
as much as their talents.
There's no such thing for us.
And I'm the only one...
She also handles other talents
but I'm the only one who
reached this level
in terms of career.
Were you in college
when you became an actor
or have you graduated already?
I was in college.
Is this your dream as a child or
you never thought
you'd be an actor?
- You didn't want to?
- I didn't want to.
I really don't want to.
I didn't have confidence
in myself before. And then,
I started gaining
a bit of confidence
when I joined pageants.
But it never crossed my mind
that I would be able
to get into this industry.
Because the people in
this industry are good looking.
Yes. That's exactly
what we were.
When you entered the industry,
that's how we were.
Yes! Ouch!
Sorry. Sorry.
I'm sorry, you had
a hard time reaching my...
- [LAUGHS]
- our standard. [LAUGHS]
Just kidding! But before,
when you were
starting out in the industry
who's the artist you
wanted to work with?
What show were you always
watching before?
Not me! My mother!
What show did she watch before?
Marimar!
When I was in grade six,
she was always the one who...
Because she is a big fan
of Filipino teleseryes
and Mexican telenovelas.
That would be around 2000s.
They're being shown
in the afternoon!
They go alongside
the 3 o'clock prayer.
Yes! After doing the laundry,
cooking lunch
that would last until dinner.
That's what she'd watch.
Yes! The telenovelas
will be shown first.
You're going to see
Marimar and Sergio!
They're kissing!
Then suddenly,
there's a commercial.
"Holy God. Holy Mighty One.
Holy Immortal One.
- 3 o'clock prayer!
- Have mercy on us
and on the whole word.
Holy God..."
Yes! Right after.
There'll be kissing then right
after, there's Sister Faustina.
What's going on?
- The segue is insane!
- The sequence is so wrong!
- But it's really Marimar.
- Yes!
At the time, my mother said,
- "Tisoy." She was really...
- [DISTANT LAUGHING]
[VICE] Why are you
laughing there?
Because what you said is true!
Sergio's being shown, suddenly
the prayer would start after.
- Oh, come on!
- Right after the kissing scene!
Your "Oh, Sergio" will turn into
"Oh, let's pray first."
[VICE] Sergio's being shown
wearing trunks...
[SEDUCTIVELY] Then
you're like "Sergio, Sergio!"
[ALDEN] Then suddenly,
"Holy God..."
[LAUGHTER]
Sometimes, the programming is
not being planned and it shows.
So, it was your mother's dream?
It was her dream that
when you became an actor,
- you can take roles like that.
- Yes! On that level.
She hopes that I'd be
a knight in shining armor
of a damsel in distress.
- Riding a horse!
- Oh my!
You didn't tell me you
- wanted to work with me!
- I said the wrong thing!
This is really where
you'd share that, huh?
Sorry, sorry!
You even talked about
a damsel in distress
when you just
want to ride a horse!
- You have a foul mouth!
- [DIVINE] He just said sorry!
Your mouth! [LAUGHS]
But...
Wasn't there a GMA
adaptation of Marimar?
[ALDEN] It starred Marian Rivera
and Dingdong Dantes.
- And Megan Young.
- You didn't auditon for that?
They didn't recreate it.
When I became an actor,
it was already done.
- I auditioned in there.
- Wow!
- [ALDEN] Wow! As?
- [DIVINE] Really?
As Corazon,
but I didn't get picked.
You're not fit for the role.
You used glutathione.
- [VERNA] Ah, Corazon?
- I'm not fit.
Who was your first crush in GMA?
[AUDIENCE] Yiee.
First showbiz crush,
not just in GMA.
- In showbiz, in general?
- Anne Curtis.
- Ah.
- Anne Curtis, really.
I don't get it. Why?
- Ah!
- [LAUGHTER]
I just can't see anything
so special about that girl.
She's so basic.
- I mean...
- [LAUGHTER]
- [DIVINE] You don't get it!
- Yes, yes, yes.
I've been with her, like,
almost everyday for the past
- 16 years.
- [ALDEN] Yes.
And I just don't see
anything special about her.
Yes. For me, she's someone
you can just, you know,
bump into...
[ALDEN] In public places.
Yes. In MRT, LRT, like that.
What is it about Anne Curtis?
Aside from being able
to eat a shoe that big.
- Eat?
- Yes.
That's her superpower!
Her mouth is so big!
- Oh my god.
- Yes!
You can even hide
a suitcase in her mouth!
Hand carry? No! Uh...
No, uh...
Normally, the first
means of attraction
comes from
the physical, right? Like...
You're looking
at me differently!
Don't mention me. Anyway!
[ALDEN LAUGHS] Physical, right?
- Like...
- Yes.
He said physical. Verna...
- Oh, I'm in.
- Yes.
Fish... Fish-ical.
- [ALDEN] A fish?
- A fish!
So, yeah. She's unique.
Anne's physicality was
very unique during that time.
I even used to call her
Ate (older sister).
- Yes.
So that's it.
And then, I'll never forget,
the first time we met
was in a school in Ortigas.
She had a full bangs back then
and she rode in
a compact orange car.
I won't mention the car's brand.
No, Anne Curtis has
a beautiful aura.
- Yes.
- Right?
It's very positive.
You'll feel a different kind
of warmth
when you're in the presence
of Anne Curtis.
- [DIVINE] Her energy!
- She has good energy.
- She has good vibes.
- Like Verna, Vice?
- Who?
- The energy?
Verna is pretty!
She just cremated alive
that's why she looked like that.
Alden, don't compare me to her.
[VICE, ALDEN] Why?
- I'm better.
- [DIVINE] You know,
Alden has this gift where
when there is
an exchange in dialogue,
he will make you feel...
- You're acting like a couple,
- [VICE] If you're his co-actor,
I've heard lots of things
like that from his co-actors,
that if you're in a scene with
him, the scene will feel real.
Yes! Especially when
he looks at you,
you'll be like,
"There you go again."
"We both feel the same way."
[LAUGHS]
Right? Oh, look at Verna.
See?
I think the music
should be sensual.
I'm going to say something here.
Oh!
- [DIVINE] Give in!
- [VICE] Verna, come here!
- Come here!
- Go there!
I'm married so I can't do
things like this anymore.
Verna, come sit here.
Before anything, I'll inform you
that I'm married too.
You're not, for now. Oh!
[AUDIENCE SCREAMING, LAUGHING]
[VERNA LAUGHING]
Why isn't it...
It seems like there's
something stopping us
from doing
what we are about to do.
I agree!
I already fell and
you didn't even catch me!
Hey!
What would you say to the women
who fantasizes about Alden?
- Sorry!
- [LAUGHTER]
- You all lost to Verna!
Alden has never done a sexy
dance before, as far as I know.
- [ALDEN] None! I'm a good boy!
- This is the first time!
- Just with Verna?
- Just with Verna.
Why did you give
her such an honor
to experience that?
Verna makes me feel like
I can be myself.
[AUDIENCE, VERNA] Wow!
I knew it! Dog really
is a man's best friend.
[VERNA] Not like that!
- Alden, be careful! My god!
- Right!
Alden, if she comes
looking for you huh,
and something happens...
I'm telling you.
Verna is a joyful person.
Yes. I just have
a question for her.
Are you willing to let me
get you pregnant?
Oh, my God!
Okay Alden, I'll think about it.
- Oh!
- Oh, look at that!
[VICE] She has distemper now,
that's why! [LAUGHS]
This is so funny!
Are you a happy child?
- That's your nature?
- I don't know!
They know that I'm like this
off cam.
I joke with them like this too.
But I'm not offering to get them
pregnant one by one.
- [LAUGHTER]
- We're only joking!
Yes! There may be people
who will get offended
by how we treat Verna.
- We're only joking here!
- [VERNA] Yes, that's true!
- Verna requested for it!
- I like it so much! Yay!
[LAUGHTER]
Besides, are you gonna get picky
when Alden joked you like that?
Right? I might even let him
impregnate my mother.
You won't hear anything from me!
Just so we can get
good looks in our genes!
Right? But you're
a happy person.
Do you like toys?
[LAUGHTER]
- No, I...
- I feel like you like toys.
- No!
- [AUDIENCE] Dogs!
- What?
- [DIVINE LAUGHS]
- Dogs?
- [VERNA] Dog?
- Your fans are harsh!
They pointed at Verna
and said, "Dogs! Dogs!"
Do you have a dog?
- I have many.
- Really?
- Eight!
- Different breeds?
Mm. But the one
I love the most is
- my aspin (Philippine dog).
- What's the name?
- Chichi!
- Aww!
I'm just going to send a picture
to the prod team,
- so we can show her.
- Chichi.
What does Chichi and Verna
have in common?
[LAUGHTER]
[DIVINE] They both like
the color orange.
- Likes the color orange!
- The difference is...
Chichi has clearer skin
than Verna!
- Really?
- Mm.
- She has a skin problem now.
- Eight?
She has a skin problem now
because of old age as well.
She's already 11 years old.
- Aww.
- She's a bit old now.
- She's a senior dog now.
- Chichi.
Our first dog was named Puchi.
- Puchi.
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, it should be like that.
I'll change your name to
Chichi tomorrow
so Alden will be reminded of you
every day.
Her name would be
Chichi Periwinkle.
- Who's that?
- [LAUGHTER]
When you were a kid,
did you excel in school?
[AUDIENCE] Yes.
I feel like I'm stupid when--
Stupid is too much!
I was stupid from grade one
until first year high school.
Why?
- Why were you stupid then?
- My grades were so low,
you'd think that
I have no plans in life.
You're just studying
because of pressure,
because your relatives
are paying for your education.
- But when...
- Who's paying for your studies?
My aunt.
Aunt Jo, my aunt from...
Actually,
all siblings pitched in.
- [VICE] Mhm.
- And my dad.
Because we struggled
a bit growing up.
So my dad, basically,
didn't earn enough from his job
to sustain the four
of us siblings.
So how are you able
to give back to them now?
Of course, as you said, before
you have a hard time in life.
They are the ones who help.
Now, you're on a
different level.
- [ALDEN] Oh, god.
- You can now buy
- ABS-CBN.
- [DIVINE LAUGHS]
It just feels so good, Vice,
like after a decade of hard work
and dedication,
and the--
Basically, our industry
is a whole world of sacrifices
- [VICE] Yes.
- in so many aspects,
- [VICE] Mhm.
- in our careers,
in the things we do
every day.
Sometimes, we don't always
like what we do.
But because we have to do it
and people expect
so much from us,
we have to do it.
So, that's 15 years of enduring.
Uh, going on 16 right now, and--
[VICE] Oh, a lot of you
might say,
"But you make so much money."
Things like that
and you're saying
you have to endure?
But it's not all about...
- ...money all the time.
- It's not just about money.
Sometimes, there are times--
We are very grateful
to this industry
for changing
our lives positively.
But there are times
when you say,
"Hmm, it's not worth it.
It hurts so much."
- Right?
- [ALDEN] Sometimes
- you've given it your all,
- [VICE] Mhm.
even your second life,
- and you're still not enough.
- [VICE] Yes.
So, that's--
I see to it that
I didn't change my
uh, standard of living.
So now, I get to splurge
on some things that
at the back of my head,
I know I worked hard for them,
so-- But the first thing I did
was secure my loved ones.
- [VICE] Aww.
- I think, uh,
that's one of my biggest--
My principles in life
and my mantra in life
is that before anything else,
you do things for the people
you care about first.
- [VICE] Mhm.
- That's just how I am.
Everyone has different
perspectives.
Right now, we live
in a generation
- with a different mindset.
- [VICE] Mhm.
But when I was in my generation,
for all the millennials
out there,
90s kids,
- uh, it was family first.
- [VICE] Mhm.
- Before yourself.
- [VICE] Yeah.
So, I did that
for the past decade.
And then, when I saw that
they were already doing okay,
like, "Oh, they're comfortable.
- More than enough.
- [VICE] Mhm.
Now it's my turn."
So, this...
[SMACKS LIPS] How do I say this?
When I was 30--
When I turned 32,
going on 34.
I'm 34 right now.
I see to it that I also get
to do things for myself,
- things that make me happy,
- [VICE] Mhm.
while, of course,
still remembering
- the people I love.
- [VICE] Yes.
[VICE] We all have
different concepts
of love and giving back,
- [ALDEN] Yes, yes.
- Right? We also have different
concepts of how
to live our lives.
Right? Some people--
For me, we're different.
For me, I come first.
- Right?
- I get it, because how else--
- I'll build myself up first.
- Yes.
- I'll make something of myself
so I have something
to share with you.
- [ALDEN] Correct, correct.
- Right? Once I--
I'll climb to the top first,
then I'll lift each one of you.
Right? I'm not the type to say,
"You all climb up
and step on me," right?
- There are people who--
- [ALDEN] Correct.
There are people who
find happiness
in seeing the people they love
in a better situation
than they are.
Right? It's different
for everyone.
- Yes.
- What's important is that
we're both doing the same thing,
what you're doing
and what I'm doing,
we're doing it
with open and happy hearts.
[ALDEN] Right, you're correct.
- That's so lovely.
- [AUDIENCE CLAPPING]
What was your most memorable
experience at school?
What's your school
in grade school?
[ALDEN] Colegio de Santa Rosa
de Lima.
- And then, uh, I feel--
- Colegio de Santa Rosa de?
- de Lima.
- That's where you graduated
- until high school?
- [ALDEN] Yes, yes.
Was it fun there?
It was fun.
[VICE] What are the things
you can't forget
that happened at that school?
What happened to you there
inside that school?
Oh, what was it?
I was often called
to the guidance office.
- I was really a bully, Vice.
- [VICE] Really?
We can't see that
you were a bully.
That you were so unruly,
and such a jerk.
I knew it.
Behind that gentle face
lives a naughty little side.
- [WHIMSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
- [PEOPLE CHEERING]
That's what you thought.
Like I said earlier,
I don't know, I think
I was talking to Chris.
Just don't-- Don't ever
give me a chance
to be a jerk-- Oh, sorry.
This will be edited anyway.
- To be a jerk--
- Oh, they're not editing this.
- Oh, don't.
- This is at 10:30PM anyway.
[ALDEN] Someone
might get mad. [LAUGHS]
[VICE, ALDEN LAUGHING]
[ALDEN] That...
This is the side of me
that I rarely get to show.
- [VICE] Yes.
- So,
- if--
- [VICE] The unruly side.
The playful side that--
So sometimes,
when I'm with my supporters
- or my fans,
- [AUDIENCE] Yes!
- that's when I get to show it.
- [VICE] Yeah.
But, that's how much
they love me.
Because even
the most censored moments
or private moments,
they never uploaded them.
- Yeah, you know, artists--
- They already know so much.
- Just like Alden.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHS]
You've been seeing him
on television for so long,
but there's so much...
His personality is so colorful,
and it would've been so nice
if he could show that.
But of course, we can't blame
other artists for holding back.
Because...
the judgment is so harsh, right?
The world is just so confusing.
The world wants you
to be true to yourself.
But once you become true
to yourself,
- they will not agree.
- [ALDEN] They will judge you.
Right? You'll get judged
if you show your true self.
Right? So... [SMACKS LIPS]
Imagine someone with such
a colorful personality,
flirty, playful, right?
Mischievous, entertaining.
If he brought that out,
watching him
would've been so much fun.
But those sides of us,
we can only show them
to people who truly
understand us.
- [AUDIENCE] Yes!
- Those who won't judge us.
That's how it is, no judgment.
Because we all
have our own quirks, right?
[ALDEN] There, when it's--
like with Divine,
whenever we see
each other outside,
she's willing to get touched.
[VERNA, AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
She'll suddenly bend over.
Stuff like that.
[VERNA, AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- [VICE] Your dignity is so low.
- [PLAYFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
No, we're just-- I said...
- Come on.
- [LAUGHTER]
No, he's really like that.
He's playful, sometimes--
Even our lunch
takes us two hours.
Then, anyway the--
Alden is such a cheerful person.
- Even if he's tired,
- [VICE] Mhm.
the only time he seems
like he's not in the mood,
he just stays quiet
in one corner,
but he's so kind, he's so--
I can't say anything bad to him.
He's also very prayerful.
Like...
There was-- The last gift
he gave me, I'm just sharing,
He got me this cross
that's like-- [STAMMERING]
That's in Italy, right?
I said, "Alden, I need something
for my car."
Something like that.
And then, he bought me one.
- Then--
- [ALDEN] St. Benedict's
- medallion crucifix.
- Yes.
- [VICE] Aww.
- After that, we kissed.
- Then...
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHS]
he said,
"That's the last one, okay?"
Just kidding! No, he's really
such a flirt, right?
- He's such a bully, so playful.
- [AUDIENCE] Yes!
But he's incredibly loving.
So much.
[VICE] Me too, because before,
when Alden and I met,
he gave me a gift too.
I was actually surprised.
I said, "We're not even
that close yet."
He gave me a gift,
it's also a cross.
Then when I looked
at it, I said,
"Why does it look like
it's upside down?"
He said,
"You're a demon, right?"
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[VICE] The cross is upside down.
[SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- [VICE LAUGHS]
- [COMICAL LAUGH SFX]
[VICE] So, what did you do
in school?
Why were you called?
I was really mischievous,
really restless.
Like? Specifically, what kind
of mischief got you called
- to the guidance office?
- I feel like growing up,
I already had undiagnosed ADHD.
It seems like everyone
in showbiz probably has that.
[ALDEN] Mm, like being
really restless, basically...
If you were told
to walk straight,
I'd walk in a zigzag.
- Automatically, even--
- Were you the type of classmate
who, when walking
down the stairs,
would do this
to someone's butt?
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- I'd push them.
- [VICE] Ah.
- I'd push them,
- I wouldn't poke their butts.
- [VICE] Ohh.
Because they were in the way,
and they walk too slowly.
- [VICE] Oh, wow--
- So, it was a little--
A little physical.
[VICE] Before, I used to get
picked on like that
all the time.
Like when you were--
You're in line, right?
- And on the stairs, they'd--
-[ALDEN] Shotgun.
They'd do this to you.
At first, I would really cry.
But when I graduated,
I found myself looking for it.
I said, "Where are
my classmates?"
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- [COMICAL LAUGH SFX]
- I went back to school.
They said, "Why are you here?
You graduated already, right?"
I said, "I just wanted to go up
the stairs."
- [LAUGHTER]
- [COMICAL LAUGH SFX]
Just so they could do this
to me there.
[ALDEN] But for Verna,
what's memorable?
Did you also like getting
this done to you
- at your school?
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
I'm also a victim of bullying.
- [VICE] Ahh.
- But I found out
that the people who bullied me
actually liked me.
- [ALDEN] Oh, my god, I knew it!
- [AUDIENCE] Ahh!
Verna, do you know
what delulu (Delusional) means?
- Have you heard of that term?
- [VERNA LAUGHING]
It's real, girl!
[DIVINE] Sorry, I was heating up
a pan
- and forgot to put the--
- [VERNA LAUGHING]
[VICE] Just cover
that woman's mouth already.
Okay, in showbiz, how many--
Oh, wait, no.
There's-- I don't know if
I watched it or read about it,
back in grade school,
you were telling a story.
- You-- You pooped your pants?
- [DIVINE] Oh my!
- [VERNA] Hey!
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
Yes.
[VICE] What grade?
- [ALDEN] High school.
- [VERNA LAUGHS]
[VICE] Oh, that's embarrassing,
because I was in grade one.
- Son of a gun.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHS]
I pooped in the classroom.
I was in grade one.
Back then, [SMACKS LIPS]
we didn't have phones.
Our landline was just a favor
from someone to make a call.
It was only like that.
So it took a long time.
They even had to go to my mom
at our house.
Then my mom only arrived when...
I was already swarmed
by a whole bunch of flies
before my mom finally got me.
So-- What year were you in?
First year.
- During first--
- Didn't you-- First year--
You were in high school, and
you still couldn't control it?
No.
Actually, up until now.
When I have to go,
I really have to go.
And my team knows that.
- You poop a lot?
- Very much.
So, name it.
The dirtiest restrooms
at gas stations?
I've taken a dump there.
Along EDSA?
[VERNA LAUGHS]
All the gas stations
along EDSA?
I've pooped in all of them.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [FLUSHING SOUNDS]
- [TETAY] Each one?
- Gosh.
You really can't control it.
[ALDEN] Because if I have to go,
I have to go.
I think that's what happened
in high school.
I really had to go.
And I probably would've been
able to hold it in,
but I think I ate something
funny during lunch.
So, that made it worse.
Like if I moved an inch,
the bomb will drop.
So, I just let go.
You probably also forgot to
bring tissues to the restroom.
[ALDEN]
It happened in the classroom.
It happened in
the classroom, Vice.
In your first year?
- Yes.
- Then what?
Who cleaned it up?
The school maintenance.
And, you see, soiling your pants
is a mortal sin for students.
Especially in high school
It doesn't matter if
you did it in the restroom
or made a mess in the classroom.
You will forever be remembered
as the guy who pooped.
They'll put it in the yearbook.
[ALDEN] Yes!
"The guy who soiled
his pants in first year."
[LAUGHTER]
- So...
- "Alden pooped."
[ALDEN] Exactly.
I know my classmates
still remember,
but they never bring it up
during reunions.
Maybe they think I'll feel
embarrassed or something.
So I bring it up myself.
"Remember when I pooped?
Remember? Okay."
- [VICE] I'll remember.
- [ALDEN] Yeah? Alright.
[ALDEN] I think that experience
really stuck with me.
How I always try
to keep it in.
So, when I got older,
- I just go when I need to go.
- You no longer hold it in.
Not anymore.
My worst experience was...
I was filming Ilustrado
at a secluded farm in Rizal.
I told Mama Ten--
She goes everywhere with me.
I told her,
"Please find a spot."
"Find a spot."
That's our code.
So, she started looking
for a spot.
Because it's not allowed
in the portalets.
Portalets aren't made
for number twos.
They're only made
for peeing.
But someone from ABS-CBN
once took a dump there.
- [ALDEN CHUCKLES]
- It became a hot topic.
- Was it a celebrity?
- Yes.
- Oh no.
- An actress.
- Oh no!
- Beautiful and sexy.
So that story became
really popular here.
The director got really mad.
She was about to pee,
so she went after the actress.
She was like,
"Who took a dump in here?!"
The actress admitted it.
She was like, "I did.
Is it not allowed?"
She didn't know.
It was her first time.
[ALDEN] My goodness.
Mama Ten helped me
look for a spot
and she found this small,
makeshift hut,
where the cowherds rest
and do their business.
The farm is that big.
I told her, "That'll do."
And, you see, I've grown used to
all kinds of restrooms.
- [VERNA] Wow!
- There's...
That really says a lot
if you've grown used
to all kinds of restrooms
after all the times
you took a dump on the road.
[ALDEN]
Yes, there are different tiers.
Some have
really low toilet seats.
Since I'm a big guy,
I have to adjust.
- What matters is--
- How do you do it?
Do you sit or squat
on the toilet?
- I sit. I can't squat.
- You don't put tissue?
No, no. I directly sit on it.
I bet your butt
is so dirty right now.
I think it's clean enough.
- You don't get--
- We can have Verna check.
- [VICE] Oh, Verna!
- [SENSUAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Why me? Fine!
[LAUGHTER]
Anyway, so there are...
There are those
with really low toilet seats
without flush.
There are toilets with flush
but aren't working.
And there are toilets
with nothing at all.
I remember it happened
in Nueva Ecija.
I really couldn't hold it in.
We stopped at a gas station.
I think it was Caltex.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
Whoever's watching
from Nueva Ecija...
We're talking about
Caltex, Nueva Ecija.
Maybe I shouldn't mention it.
Please cut that out.
- You find out which one.
- Yeah, but...
Well, before I go, I always
have someone check first.
[VICE] Wow, you have
a location manager...
- [LAUGHTER]
- ...for public restrooms!
He'd be like, "Please check."
And they'd say, "Alden, clear."
- [LAUGHTER]
- That's what Mama Ten does!
Since she has motion sickness...
Isn't it obvious?
Just kidding.
So, she'd go first
while I wait in the car.
She'd check the restrooms first.
But this time,
I couldn't hold it in,
so I called her to hurry up.
If you think actors are perfect,
you're wrong.
We have disgusting sides too.
And we can't help it.
But going back to my story
about that farm in Rizal...
So, I went inside the hut.
It looked decent enough.
The restroom was closed off.
So, I went inside.
When I entered the restroom,
I was like, "Ma, is this it?"
She said yes,
so I was like, "Where?"
Because all I saw
was a small hole in the ground.
[VICE] What an experience.
Have you told that story
to your previous girlfriends?
- No.
- [VICE LAUGHS]
You kept it from your
previous girlfriends,
but you shared it with
so many people tonight.
How many girlfriends
have you had?
With proper label, only two.
- Just two.
- How old are you?
Thirty-four.
Just two? Did they last?
It happened
back in high school.
[VICE] Non-showbiz?
All the relationships I've had
since I entered showbiz...
None of them became official.
I'd connect with them,
but nothing came of it.
- Maybe it's not meant for me.
- [VICE] You mean...
...almost-but-not-quite
relationships?
None of them became official.
I don't know why.
I don't want to
name names anymore.
You've already heard it
on the news anyway.
I won't mention their names
and bother them anymore.
[VICE] Aww.
- You fell in love with them?
- Of course. Yes.
How many women have you
been involved with in showbiz?
- Five.
- Oh, five?
- Five situationships?
- Yes.
Why do you think
none of them worked out?
I don't know either.
Maybe I'm the problem.
- Maybe--
- Who breaks it off?
Sometimes, me.
Sometimes, the other party.
But the last one,
she broke it off.
Shit. Sorry.
[OVERLAPPING CHATTER
FROM AUDIENCE]
Your eyes changed.
The last one...
[VICE] She pulled back?
We both did,
but it's more on her.
Why?
I think, um...
[VICE]
I'm so curious. Wait.
[LAUGHTER]
I wanna be in the know.
Come closer. [CHUCKLES]
Why did she break it off?
What was her reason?
Cris! Vice is asking
too many questions!
No, um...
How do I explain it?
Uh...
It's hard. I feel like it's not
my piece to say.
- I shouldn't speak for her.
- Okay, just tell us your side.
What's the reason
you pulled back?
You said you both pulled back.
But what was your reason?
I think what I learned
from my experience
with that relationship
is never say never.
Don't give yourself
an ultimatum
because you're too
happy with the situation.
I ate my words.
- And--
- Then, you had to poo.
- Yeah.
- [LAUGHTER]
I had to go straight
to the toilet.
- Yeah.
- He had to pull back
because had to go
take a dump at the gas station.
- Because I ate my words.
- [LAUGHS]
I guess it just happened.
You also said there were times
when it was you who pulled back.
- Yes.
- How do you say that...
to a woman that...
...you no longer want
that relationship?
Do you just walk away?
For the first one,
I walked away without a word.
- I ghosted her. Mm-hmm.
- [VICE] Oh...
Which is not...
Uh...
Not good.
[VICE] Verna's okay
with being ghosted.
- Oh? But I thought--
- It's fine. I'll cling to you.
I thought you were the ghost.
- I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
- Her real name is Casper.
[LAUGHTER]
So, what about the rest
if you ghosted the first one?
You talked before you left?
Yes, we talked.
I mean, you know...
We learn from every circumstance
that happens in our lives.
But when it comes to love...
I feel like I've been
very unlucky with love
for the past 15 years
because I kept chasing it.
- [VICE] Ah.
- Because the fact that...
...I haven't started a family
at my age worries me.
- You feel pressured?
- Yes. That's how Pinoys are.
We live in a culture
of deadlines.
You have to be this or that
at a certain age.
But I don't think that's how I
want to live my life right now.
So, after the last one...
I decided to stop chasing love.
I'll live my life by accepting
whatever God sends my way,
may it be a circumstance,
a person...
I'm not saying I won't
fall in love anymore.
I'm not saying I've stopped
or I'm no longer waiting
for the right person to come.
Because for the longest time,
I actively searched for the one.
So maybe, for a change,
I should just wait for them.
You're just letting them
come your way.
You're no longer going out
of your way to meet them.
You're no longer trying
to find them.
I mean,
I already failed five times.
So, maybe I should
change gears.
[VICE] No, that's true.
Sometimes,
you really won't find it
if you actively keep
looking for it, right?
But when you just
leave it to fate,
it'll just surprise you.
It's like... It's like...
Like love is playing
hard to get.
When you want it,
you can't find it.
But when you let go,
it just finds you.
I'd compare it with...
It's like holding sand.
The more you try
to tighten your grip,
the more sand
escapes your fingers,
as opposed to just letting it
sit on your palm.
Somewhere out there,
I know that...
How many are we?
There are seven billion
people in the world.
I'm sure one of them
is meant for me.
- Yes.
- Aww!
For sure there's one person...
who will love and accept you
for who you are
and be brave enough
to fight for you.
That's so nice to hear.
So many people
can learn to love you.
And he can learn
to love them back.
But the question is,
will they fight for it?
Which one of them
will fight for your love?
Right?
And you'll be surprised.
When that person comes...
...she won't be
who you imagined her to be.
She won't be like you expected.
She won't be like you pictured
in your mind.
She may not even be
the one you asked for.
You might find
yourself thinking,
"You're not the one I asked for,
but you make me feel the love
that I've always longed for."
If it happens, It happens.
If it comes, it comes.
If it's there, it's there.
There's really
nothing you can do.
When it happens,
there's nothing you can do.
Because even if you want
something so badly,
if it's not the right time,
it won't work out.
I feel like that's what
has been happening.
And just like your iconic line
from your iconic TV segment,
"At the right time."
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYING]
- Great.
- Yeah.
You may feel like relationships
aren't for you now.
Like complications always
arise whenever you find love.
And so you stop trying
because you think
you're better off without them.
But that's not true.
Genuine love feels so good.
Maybe it's also because...
For the longest time,
I've been trying to find love
from other people.
But I realized...
what I lacked was self-love.
[AUDIENCE] Aww!
- Aww!
- Don't cry, Alden!
- It's okay!
- You'll be fine!
[TENDER MUSIC PLAYING]
[TENDER MUSIC CONTINUES]
It took so long before I...
[BREATHING DEEPLY]
[VICE] I told you to come
only when you're called.
Where's her leash?!
[TETAY] She ate it because
no one gave her treats!
[VERNA CHUCKLES]
[TETAY] Aww! Tisoy!
[VICE] I... I understand.
Yeah. Believe me,
I understand.
I've been there.
[VERNA] Aww!
[VICE] Yeah.
And I know it's hard.
But at least now,
you're acknowledging it.
It's very important that
you acknowledge it.
Like, "Oh, maybe I should
find love for myself.
Because I kept looking for it
from other people
that I ended up forgetting
to love myself."
We keep longing
for someone else's love
that we sometimes forget
we can give that to ourselves.
And that love is
already inside us.
And because your heart
is very generous,
you have been giving so much
to the world.
[TENDER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SOBBING]
I'm sorry, Vice.
[TENDER MUSIC CONTINUES]
Vice, I don't usually
let this out because...
[VICE] Sorry if there's
something we said
that triggered you.
No, actually, coming here,
I feel like...
this is the first time
I've really been able to say it.
[SNIFFLES]
All my life, I've just...
felt like...
[INAUDIBLE]
[SOBBING]
[TENDER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[VICE] We understand.
[ALDEN SOBBING]
I'm sorry.
[TENDER MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [EXHALES DEEPLY]
- [VICE] Breathe.
[VICE] Breathe.
Breathe through your nose.
Hold... release.
[ALDEN BREATHES DEEPLY]
It's okay.
Sorry, guys.
[APPLAUSE]
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
[LAUGHTER]
[VICE] Get out!
[INAUDIBLE]
It feels so good.
- That was deep.
- Yes.
[INAUDIBLE]
I even let it all out here.
Thank you.
[INAUDIBLE]
[ALDEN SIGHS]
Breathe, just breathe.
[ALDEN EXHALES DEEPLY]
I think we've gone over
an hour already.
- Is that okay?
- It's okay.
Miss Arvs, are you there?
[INAUDIBLE]
I'll tell you later
after the taping.
[INAUDIBLE]
Hey, Arvie!
- Hi.
- My makeup artist.
[INAUDIBLE]
[VERNA CHUCKLES]
You know, little by little,
he realized,
"Shit, what I did...
I didn't like how it felt
doing that to Verna earlier."
[LAUGHTER]
He was filled with regret.
Yeah, he said, "I did something
I can't accept."
- That's what triggered me.
- [VERNA] You got triggered?
- He couldn't accept it.
- But it's such a nice trigger.
[VERNA] Ah!
So good.
[LAUGHTER]
Okay.
Since you've already been
sharing some things with us,
I realized how nosy I am,
so I came closer because
I really wanted to hear.
Since you've already shared
some things with us,
okay, for this new season
of GGV,
we've got a new segment.
Alden will be revealing
something explosive.
You guys like that
kind of stuff?
- [AUDIENCE CHEERING]
- Explosive revelations!
Since the Philippines is
full of certified gossipers,
this is exactly what they want.
We're going to call this...
Deep Truth.
[LAUGHTER]
Yes.
Among us gays,
we call it Deep Trot.
Trot? Or Charot?
It's Trot. Deep Trot.
In Deep Truth, our guest
will reveal a deep statement.
Through questioning
and analyzing, my...
Genggang,
Verna and Tetay, and I,
have to guess if
the deep statement
is Trot (Truth)
or Charot (Lie).
Whoever gets the wrong guess
or judgment
will face a deep punishment.
We'll all find out
what that is later.
Okay, Alden!
You're the very first person
to do this segment.
- Deep Truth.
- Yes, I'm ready.
Ready? Where are they?
You two, come here.
Let's listen to Alden first.
Whatever his deep statement is.
Alden, they said you wrote
your deep statement here.
Wow, it looks like
an actual court statement.
[TETAY] Yes!
Alden, go ahead and read it.
What is Alden Richards'
deep statement?
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Okay, so...
You'll read
what's written there,
then show it to us
for clarification.
- For clarification?!
- Here you go...
I don't know,
this is pretty easy.
"I punched someone
because they called me gay."
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
Where was that?
- Where?
- Laguna.
When I was a child.
Oh, so this wasn't when
you were already an actor?
- Childhood.
- Yeah.
You punched someone?
[AUDIENCE CHEERING]
But didn't he just tell us
earlier
that he had that kind
of personality?
Didn't he used to push
people down the stairs?
Yeah, remember when someone
got hit by a train at the MRT
because he pushed them?
That was him.
- No!
- Hey, wait!
- Wasn't that you?
- That wasn't him.
Didn't he used to be a bully?
And he was mischievous, right?
- I feel like...
- How was that?
- Like this...
- Like a Boyoyong Clown?
[LAUGHTER]
Boing!
He was pretty
mischievous, right?
I feel like he was
capable of doing that.
According to Lovely.
Where was it?
At school, on the street,
at the basketball court?
- At the playground?
- At school.
Didn't he get called?
He was always
at the guidance office.
[PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES]
How did you punch him?
Like this.
[LAUGHTER]
- Show her, please.
- [ALDEN] I punched him...
Where did you hit him?
I punched him with my lips.
[TETAY] Oh.
- You're beautiful!
- He's really into me!
[CHUCKLES] Confirmed!
It's like he couldn't
help himself, huh?
He said he punched him
in the lips?
- With my lips.
- Oh, with his lips.
He punched him with his lips.
How?
[LAUGHTER]
- This janitor fish is wild.
- She is.
But where did you punch him?
Which part?
The face, the side...
Maybe the chest? Here.
[VICE] Oh.
Did you really hurt him?
- I'm not sure.
- Did he fight back?
No.
So it wasn't really a fight.
- You just got one hit in?
- Yes.
Ah, so he didn't fight back?
- Basically...
- Yeah, he got to him first.
"What?!"
Pow, like that.
[ALDEN] No, it had
a different tone. "What?!"
"What?! Are you a fish
or a dog?"
[LAUGHTER]
I'm getting confused with you.
You're breathing here.
[CHUCKLING] Like gills?
The problem is,
you bark in an aquarium.
This makes no sense!
[VERNA CHUCKLING]
Fighting dog or fighting fish?
RottweiFish, just kidding.
[TETAY] What's your question?
This is too hard.
- I don't know.
- [VICE] Just ask questions.
Interrogate him.
- [SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
- Were you alone at the time?
Was anyone else with you
when the incident occurred?
Were you provoked?
- No, I was on my own.
- You were alone.
Would you say that you found
your courage that very day?
- Yes.
- [VERNA] Oh my!
[VICE] Did your parents
see you when you did this?
[ALDEN] No.
Did the parents see you
when you did this to their son?
[ALDEN] No.
Did you ever regret this thing?
No.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[VERNA]
Not even an ounce of regret.
He was furious.
When you punched him, was that
the first time he provoked you,
or it was multiple times then
that you snapped?
[ALDEN] Many times, Your Honor.
[TETAY CHUCKLES]
He deserved it.
[VICE] You punched someone
he called you gay.
- Is he still alive?
- Yes.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
It's time for us to vote.
[TETAY] Sure.
Remember, if any of us
makes a mistake,
they will get punished.
So we need to be smart
about this.
What do you think?
Trot or Charot?
[AUDIENCE SHOUTING]
[TETAY] What?
[VICE] Trot or Charot?
[OVERLAPPING SHOUTING]
[VICE] Well, he said he was
that kind of boy back then.
I'm going with Trot.
But he looks like a gentleman.
You can be the kindest person,
but a bastard always deserves
a punch in the face.
- Yeah.
- I should know.
So what did you do
when they called you that?
I hit a lot of people as a kid.
- Yeah?
- [CHUCKLES]
They could call me gay
all they wanted.
Just not within earshot
of my father.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [SILLY SFX]
If he was close enough
to hear it, we'd have a problem.
I'm choosing Trot.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
I'm going with Charot.
I'm basing my answer
on how naughty he was as a kid.
He was probably capable of it.
It was just a punch
on the chest.
So... Trot.
You're both Trot?
Trot all the way.
What, you don't want to join us?
[LAUGHTER]
You really want to be different?
Alright. You'd better not
show up in the next episode.
- [SILLY SFX]
- [CHUCKLES AWKWARDLY]
- Actually, I'm choosing Trot.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
Her answer's Trot.
I've got an idea for a title.
Good Evening Verna.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [LAUGH TRACK PLAYS]
Good Evening Vulldog.
You're both going with Trot.
Everyone having the same
answer is boring, though.
I'm picking Charot.
- Now, wait a second!
- Oh, come on!
I mean, it's not fun at all.
Right?
We want some variety,
some excitement.
If the statement was true,
no one would get punished.
That would be lame.
So, my answer is Charot
for that reason.
Both of us are here
because we believe in unity.
So whatever you decide,
it's the same for us.
- That's right.
- We don't want to leave you.
- You know?
- No, no.
You know me.
When it comes to punishment,
I'd rather take it
than you guys.
Aww!
We're friends.
- We don't want to leave you.
- You're old.
- I just want you to be happy...
- Wow.
- ...in your final years.
- You know what?
You may be the Phenomenal Star,
but I can still slap you.
I don't care
if you're Vice Ganda.
I've had it with you, brat.
Now, where are my slippers?
Please no.
So, final answer.
You're both choosing Trot?
- Oh no, it broke.
- My goodness.
And it's your first time
using it.
You're Charot,
while we're both Trot.
- Trot...
- I'm picking Charot.
Okay, we're going with Trot.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
You're both Trot,
while I'm Charot.
How about our studio audience?
[AUDIENCE] Charot!
[VICE] What?
You were all riding
the Trot wagon a while ago!
I get it. You're just copying
your answer from them!
Because you know
they're die-hard fans!
Raise your hand
if you're a Trot believer!
[INDISTINCT AUDIENCE CHATTER]
Front row people,
you were all in on Trot!
You're all crazy!
[LAUGH TRACK PLAYS]
But now you're all
on the Charot side.
Okay. Again, there's a
punishment for this.
Okay.
Alden...
Your Deep Statement is...
"I punched someone because
they called me gay."
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[VICE] You hit someone
after being called gay.
Is it Trot... or Charot?
[AUDIENCE SHOUTING]
[VERNA] Trot! Trot!
Trot!
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Charot.
- [BUZZER BLARES]
- [VICE] Oh my!
[CACKLING]
- That was a test.
- Meme!
Hang on,
let's hear his explanation.
Why Charot?
So it didn't happen at all?
[ALDEN] There was
no such thing, actually.
- Oh, really?
- No, no, no.
So...
That was from the genius
of Chris and the writing team.
[VICE] But you always hear
the same line, don't you?
- You've been asked many times.
- Absolutely!
Did you ever come close
to choosing violence?
- Ah, not really.
- [CHUCKLES]
I get annoyed, though.
And offended.
I mean...
Where's my baby picture?
[VICE] Where is it?
You came here with his picture?
[TETAY] Let's see it!
There. My baby picture.
When you look like that
in the province,
someone who's fair-skinned
- and with smooth skin...
- Show us, please!
[VERNA] We want to see!
What's the holdup?
You were raising it earlier.
[CHUCKLES]
That face's asking for it.
[VICE] You were the spitting
image of Niño Muhlach!
[ALDEN] Yes, that's it.
Like a Niño Muhlach clone!
[ALDEN] With that face,
you get called gay.
I can see another resemblance.
Julie Andrews
of The Sound of Music
in her teenage years.
- [VERNA] Aww!
- That's what I looked like.
[VICE] Because the questions
kept being repeated,
you eventually
got annoyed, right?
The questions never stopped,
even after I entered showbiz.
In this industry,
for some reason
you need to have a girlfriend
to be considered a man.
[VICE] How many times does
that need to be asked?
How many times does
that need to be answered?
[ALDEN] Yes. I've learned
to ignore it.
I mean, I...
I only truly understood it
probably in my fifth year
in the industry.
That other people's prejudice
means nothing.
There are only three kinds
of truth out there.
Their truth, your truth,
and the actual truth.
[VICE] Yes.
So at the end of the day,
to save myself from explaining,
and to invalidate
the same-old rumors...
- Let them come.
- [VICE] You don't give a damn.
No matter what you say,
they won't listen.
They just believe
what they want.
- So, what now?
- That's your problem now.
Exactly. And listen to this:
I'm speaking from my experience.
Nobody ever gossiped
that I was gay.
- [AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
- [BRIGHT MUSIC PLAYING]
Right?
Really, no one asked me that.
[LAUGHTER]
It's kind of weird, right?
No one gossiped about it.
They just assumed it.
But, there is a punishment.
For your punishment,
you'll have to cool down.
- Huh?
- How exactly?
- You'll cool down deep inside.
- A chill to the bones.
An ice cube will be placed
inside your clothes,
down to your shorts or pants,
and you have to get it out.
Where are the ice cubes?
[LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING]
Don't worry.
Alden will put it in.
Okay! [CHUCKLES]
[TETAY] Gosh! That's huge!
- [OOHING]
- [VERNA CHUCKLES]
[VICE] Here you go.
Nobody mentioned
they were small, right?
[LAUGH TRACK PLAYS]
Right?
You don't need to do anything.
Alden, please put it in.
Let's start with Tetay.
- Just anywhere?
- Yes.
Drop it in his shirt, and it has
to come out of his pants.
Yes.
Go!
[LIVELY MUSIC CONTINUES]
Look, Alden removed the plastic!
Honestly, I can open up
my pants for him.
- But that's massive, Alden.
- Go, Alden! Go!
From his shirt
down to his pants.
From the shirt?
Then all the way down?
- Then out of my pants?
- Go!
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
[VERNA] Chilling!
[SILLY SFX]
[VICE]
It needs to enter his pants.
[LAUGH TRACK PLAYS]
[AUDIENCE SQUEALING]
[VICE]
Wow, it just slid right out!
Verna, it's your turn.
Meme, I was on Team Charot.
- Hang on--
- Let's see...
...if the ice cube will slip
straight down and out.
Hurry up! His hand is
getting cold already!
Close your eyes, Alden,
while you put it in.
Shake your clothes while
his eyes are closed.
Yes!
Yay!
That's a fun punishment.
We enjoyed the punishment.
[CHUCKLES]
The casting of the four
of us here seems perfect.
I hope we can do
a project together.
And with these two as well.
But what if we do a--
Vertical dramas
are pretty trending right now.
- [ALDEN] Yes, yes.
- Those...
[ALDEN] What's the story,
what's the concept?
I like those AI dramas...
- The box dramas...
- The Chinese ones.
What?
Yes, that kind of stuff.
For instance--
You're really eating pansit
again while we're in this?!
He biked here.
The scene is
that we're together.
And your mom doesn't like me.
Tetay's your mom.
Wow, I always get the mom role.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
Mom or dad?
Which do you like more?
Fine, I'll be the mom.
- Right?
So that's the scene.
We're together and your mom
doesn't like me.
But there's a catch.
- [VERNA] What?
- There is a catch.
- Catch it. I'm kidding.
- [LAUGHTER]
There's a catch.
You always have
to include this word--
Whenever you say your line,
you need to insert
'Baguio' in it.
- Okay.
- But you're going to say it
the way you did,
that became very iconic.
Let's watch this.
That's not you.
That's still me, Alden.
- Baguio!
- Oh, yeah.
Baguio!
- Why were...
- Baguio!
- What's your beef with Baguio?
Baguio!
No-- [CHUCKLES] How...
What's your beef with Baguio?
No, the problem was,
the audio inside the MOA Arena
was different from the audio
reception online, on YouTube.
I was yelling
because the arena is huge.
[VICE]
You didn't have a monitor?
There's none--
I wasn't sure if it was working.
But inside the MOA Arena,
it was okay.
- Ahh.
- But--
But onstage, you can't hear
the level of your mic.
No. I didn't know I was yelling
on the live stream.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
In our dialogue, you need to
insert that word in your lines.
You need to say 'Baguio'
in that manner.
- Okay.
We're together
and you'll oppose it.
[TETAY] Okay, so I'm like
the rich mom,
- and then...
- Yes.
But you look rich.
She's wearing Chanel.
- [ALDEN LAUGHS]
- From head to boots.
There's two.
Chanel and Channel 2.
- Or Channel 7. Okay.
- Okay.
So the scene is
I'll introduce you to them.
- She'll arrive.
- Oh, okay.
Yes, pretend we're at home.
You brought me
into your home.
The title of the show
is Hello, Love, AI.
- [VERNA LAUGHS]
- Why AI?
- What?
[ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING]
- You have a poster!
- It's a nice poster, Alden!
There. Hello, Love, AI.
That's his name.
Alden Ichards.
[LAUGHTER]
[TETAY] That's why it's AI.
- Yes. It has a subtitle.
- What is it?
Hello, Love, AI delas Alas.
- [LAUGHS] Oh, I see.
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
Hey, I look pretty here. What?
I'll ask someone
to do this look for me.
I'll do that hair next time.
I can do that.
Alden looks handsome.
- [TETAY] Super, right?
- Okay.
Game.
Lights, camera, action.
- Let's wait for Mommy.
- [ROMANTIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
But I really enjoyed...
Why did you take me here?
[LAUGHTER]
- This isn't Memerimar.
- [ALDEN LAUGHS]
I'm doing the Memerimar bit.
Uh, I'm embarrassed to be here.
I feel like I don't belong here.
- Your house is so big.
- No, it's okay.
It's okay.
I'm happy we're here now
because I had a lot of fun
when we were in Baguio!
[CROWD LAUGHS]
[LAUGH TRACK PLAYING]
[VICE CHUCKLES]
I didn't know
you'd say it right away.
- [LAUGHS]
- [LAUGHS, APPLAUSE]
[CROWD CHEERING]
I wasn't ready.
Your house is huge.
Who else lives here?
Uh, my mom and I
are the only ones here.
But your mom
isn't here now, right?
- [TETAY] Alden?
- Uh, Ma.
You witch, don't come in yet.
We'll flirt first.
- I just read this.
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- Alden?
- I haven't made a move.
Darn it.
[TETAY] Please continue.
You and your mom
are the only ones here?
- Mm-hmm.
- But now, who's here?
Uh...
I think our lawyer is here,
but my mom and I
are the only ones here.
But now it's just the two of us.
Yeah, she went to the salon.
Oh.
I think you want us
to do something
that's why you brought me here.
Uh, I'm glad we're here now.
But I miss the times
when you were sweet to me.
You gave me ube, remember?
- Where did you buy that?
- Ah, yeah.
It's specially made.
It's from Good Shepherd.
There are actually two branches.
One in Tagaytay
and one in Baguio!
- [LAUGHTER]
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
- Is it fun there?
- Mm-hmm.
Why do the people there
seem mad?
They seem to get mad easily.
Oh, I'm scared.
I hope someone else arrives
because you seem to have
anger management issues.
- Uh...
- [TETAY] Alden!
- Oh! Who's that?
- Ma. Ma.
Anger seems to run
in your family.
- [TETAY GROWLS]
- You're always yelling.
Alden, you left the door open--
[GASPS]
Sorry, Ma.
Where has she been?
Was she out of town?
She just got home from Baguio!
[CROWD LAUGHS]
Uh, I hope you don't
come there again.
Alden, who's your guest?
Mom, I'd like you to meet my...
- Who is that?
- My girlfriend, Mom.
Where is she?
Your mom's blind?
[LAUGHTER]
Your girl-- [CHUCKLES]
You told me she's skinny.
Why does she feel fat?
Your mom seems to be good
at mahjong.
Mom, that's our couch, Mom.
- Who is she?
- Mom.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
She's the one
I was telling you about.
I met her in Baguio!
[LAUGHTER]
Every time you shout,
my hairline moves back.
[LAUGHTER]
You know...
are you serious about her?
That kind of girl,
the only thing she wants
is our money.
- Mom, I don't think so, Mom.
- [TETAY] Oh, come on!
How long have you
been dating her?
- Three hours, Mom.
- Excuse me.
Where did you meet her?
Baguio!
[LAUGHTER]
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
I don't intend
to disrespect you,
but your mom
is saying hurtful things to me.
- Look, dear--
- Who really is she?
- My mom. She's my mom.
- How is she your mom?
That's Joey Marquez.
- [LAUGHTER]
- [SILLY SFX PLAYING]
Son, what's this--
He used to be a PBA player,
and became an actor.
How is that your mom?
Son, your girlfriend is rude!
Your mom is pretty big.
I'll spank his mouth,
you'll see!
[SILLY SFX PLAYING]
Can't you defend me
from your mom?
Mom, you motherfather.
Yes.
Sometimes I'm a mommy.
Sometimes I'm a father.
[LAUGHING SFX]
Why are you like that
to my baby?
Alden, you just choose.
If you pick her,
you won't get anything from me,
not even a cock-eyed cent.
How did that happen, Mom?
- That a cent became cock-eyed?
- It went like this.
[LAUGHTER]
If you can't defend me,
I'll just leave.
Wait a minute, don't--
Wait.
- [VICE GROANS]
- Wow!
[ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING]
It smells like pansit.
[LAUGHS]
With ketchup.
I smelled the pansit
with ketchup.
But if this is how
our relationship would be...
It's like I'm in hell.
It's too hot.
- [TETAY] That's right!
- I want to go someplace cold.
- Come on. Mom.
- Yes?
I'm choosing her.
- Oh my god.
- Don't look for us anymore
because we're going back
to Baguio!
[GRUNTING]
Baguio, Mom!
[VICE]
You have a bad personality.
Go to Baguio!
Look at the attitude
of the person you want to marry.
You don't even know
her family background.
She's just a gold digger.
Look at her clothes!
They're much better than mine.
- Look. Look!
- So, Mom,
that's where I'm confused.
Who really is--
Maybe she can sustain
my lifestyle more than you.
You want to have a child
with her, Alden?
Yes, Mom!
If you really love me,
prove it.
- Slap your mother.
- [TETAY] Huh?
Will you slap your mother,
or I will?
Just slap my mom.
You've been at it
since earlier.
You're already hurting
my feelings.
You're a mom,
but your hands are big.
My dad played basketball.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
[LAUGHING SFX]
Oh no.
I won't let you keep treating me
this way.
- You don't know me.
- I know you.
You don't know me.
You're a low-class person, dear.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
You're the kind of woman
who's only after our money!
Those clothes you wear
as if you're--
I will not allow myself
to be treated like this.
- It's time you meet her.
- Huh? Who?
I won't let your mother
belittle me,
- so I brought our attorney.
- Okay.
- Attorney.
- This is the attorney.
She's Atty. Kaponyan
(she's neutered).
- [ALDEN] Kaponyan?
- What's her name?
- [VICE] Kaponyan.
- Am I a dog?
Yes, you're an aboga-dog
(attorney dog).
She's Atty. Kaponyan.
- Why--
- She's belittling me.
- Love, come here, love!
Why are you belittling
my client?
Stop it. I'll get a jar,
and put you inside.
Didn't you know she's an heiress
of the Sterling family?
Wow. I knew it.
I knew it.
She came from a wealthy family!
- [TETAY] What?!
- And that's not all.
She's very intelligent.
She scored 719 in her math exam!
Wow, I knew it.
I am Linda Runner.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
- [ALDEN] That's Mom's favorite.
- [TETAY] Is it true?
Is what you are saying all true?
Yes!
Therefore, you have no right
to belittle her!
Don't yell at my mother!
Therefore, you have no right
to belittle her! Oh.
I'm your client!
Therefore, you have no right
to belittle her!
Don't you remember her?
- Babe. Who is--
- We bought her.
She's the ashtray.
She had a round thing.
We bought her from--
Where did we go again?
- The one that goes like this?
- Yes!
- And then this comes out?
- In Baguio!
- Ah!
In Bag--
- There.
- Sorry.
- Don't hurt her.
- The relationships
- are confusing me.
- Wait!
I want you to know...
Ever since you lost
your mother...
Attorney and I got closer.
Wow, your mom flirts
with a spider inside a matchbox.
[LAUGHING SFX]
Please forgive me.
I didn't mean to...
- ...say those things to you.
- [VICE] Don't worry.
- They're being possessed.
- My parents taught me
not to fight with the elderly.
- Wow.
- And I shouldn't harbor
resentment and anger
towards anyone.
I love your son.
And I forgive you.
Thank you very much.
You won't hear anything bad
from me.
- But I know you move fast.
- No.
I've known you
for more than two decades.
- I forgive you.
- Thank you.
- I'm a good person.
And I won't ever do something
ill towards you.
Thank you, Sarah.
Please forgive me.
I love your mother more.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHS, SCREAMS]
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
Let's give a round of applause
to Alden!
- [ALDEN] Woo!
- Yay!
[VICE]
Alden, thank you very much.
I had so, so, so, so,
so much fun tonight!
It is, um...
It was more
than what I expected,
to tell you honestly, Vice.
To the entire creatives team,
thank you for having me here.
This is now my core memory.
This is very life-changing
for me.
One of the highlights,
not of 2026, but my life.
I would like to consider
this opportunity--
I'm not exaggerating here.
But I had a lot of moments,
so I feel very blessed
to be here.
Thank you very much.
I am just so happy
to see you enjoying yourself,
the set, us, and everyone,
and just being yourself,
and having so much fun.
I always see you ever since.
I watch you, I admire you.
I find you handsome,
I find you kind.
But your personality
is just so colorful!
There's still so much
we don't know about you.
And when we see you,
you're so happy.
Your aura feels so light.
And I hope that many people
around the world can see
that Alden is more than just a
pretty face and a talented guy.
- [TETAY] True.
- He's a guy--
He's an ordinary guy,
and yet he's special.
But he's just like us.
He feels a lot, he does a lot,
he fools around a lot,
he has a lot...
He has a lot of strengths
and weaknesses.
He has a lot of imperfections,
but still, he's very special.
And thank you so much
for treating
this program very special
because you did a lot of things
we only saw
- you do for the first time.
- Yes, a lot!
And stories you told
for the first time.
It's the first time I danced...
...in front of a
very beautiful dilag (woman).
[CHUCKLING]
- That's nothing.
- Dalag (mudfish), sorry.
I meant a very beautiful dalag.
- Dalag.
- A very beautiful dalag.
- We're hard to catch.
- [ALDEN LAUGHS]
We're quite slippery.
- Sorry.
- But thank you.
We appreciate you.
We're glad that you're our guest
for our first episode!
[CHEERING]
We did it!
Our first episode of GGV on GMA!
Certified fresh.
Fresh episode, fresh guest,
fresh stories, fresh fun
and everything under the sun.
Thank you so much,
Alden Richards!
Thank you, Vice.
Thank you to everyone
behind Gandang Gabi, Vice!
Thank you as well to
our Kapamilyas and Kapusos
who watched the pilot episode.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
What's your new show?
- You're shooting it now, right?
- Oh!
Please watch out for
Love, Siargao,
a Viu Original series.
It will air on September 28,
Monday to Friday, at 9:35 PM
on GMA Prime.
And of course, next year,
my medical drama
will finally air.
It's called Code Gray.
And I'm very excited
about this project
because it's the first time
that I'm going to be
portraying a surgeon
who saves lives.
So we're going to be
tackling the drama
and the struggles
of the healthcare situation
here in the Philippines.
What are the struggles
of doctors and surgeons?
- And the patients.
- Yes, the patients' struggles.
Doctors seem to be
perfect, they know everything,
but there is a flaw
in the system.
So stay tuned for
Code Gray next year on GMA.
And, I'll grab the opportunity,
Vice...
[VICE] Go ahead!
On November 7,
produced by
Myriad Productions,
we'll be hosting Fun Ride PH.
It's a tourism cycling event
in partnership with DOT.
So I hope you can join us.
That's going to take place
at the Quirino Grandstand.
We'll tour around
the scenic sites of Metro Manila
on Roxas Boulevard, Luneta Park,
and Intramuros.
That's a long route.
On November 7?
November 7!
So, uh, see you guys there.
Thank you, Alden!
You can watch the GGV
Unfiltered Version on iWant.
Feel the laughter worldwide.
Subscribe to iWant.
And of course,
of course, of course...
Thank you to the people
who provided our new furniture.
- Beautiful.
- Thank you very much,
Buddhism Furniture Design House,
for our furniture pieces
here in the studio.
Thank you to Expert for
providing our food carts.
Thank you very much.
Happy birthday to our
head of non-scripted formats,
Sir Louie!
- Happy birthday, Sir Louie!!
- Sir Louie, happy birthday!
Kapamilya, Kapuso,
see you next week
here at your favorite
Sunday night habit...
[IN UNISON]
Gandang Gabi, Vice!
It's time to party and
celebrate this new blessing!